<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Wade Wegner</title>
    <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Wade Wegner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 15:06:27 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.wadewegner.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Training Week-In-Review: January 8, 2023</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2023/01/training-week-in-review-january-8-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 15:06:27 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2023/01/training-week-in-review-january-8-2023/</guid>
      <description>Playing &amp;ldquo;bump&amp;rdquo; with my son and wife during the week.
I think this past week marked a turning point for my training. The last few months have brought challenges that were new for me, and consequently I struggled with recovery and rest. I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to debug and resolve most of those issues, and as a result feel as if I&amp;rsquo;m headed in the right direction.
As this is my first &amp;ldquo;Week-In-Review&amp;rdquo; post, I&amp;rsquo;ll share a few things to set some context:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Return to Blogging</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2023/01/my-return-to-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 15:12:02 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2023/01/my-return-to-blogging/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve sat down and written a blog post. I&amp;rsquo;m humbled to say it took me a few hours to relearn Hugo and get it functioning on my PC. But this post isn&amp;rsquo;t about Hugo, migrating from GitHub Pages to Netlify, nor my decision to archive 12 years of old blog posts.
This blog post is to say, well, I have things I want to say.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mahalo a Aloha, Salesforce</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2021/01/mahalo-a-aloha-salesforce/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 14:56:45 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2021/01/mahalo-a-aloha-salesforce/</guid>
      <description>I never thought I’d be writing this blog post, yet here I am. After an incredible five years at Salesforce, it’s time to say “Mahalo a Aloha,” or thank you and goodbye.
I have so much gratitude for my colleagues at Salesforce, our customers, and of course, the fantastic Salesforce community. Never in my career have I felt the sense of mission that I have at Salesforce. The desire to advance the “state-of-the-art” for Salesforce developers was a passion reciprocated by my colleagues, supported by leadership, and always appreciated by our customers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
