<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wade Wegner</title>
    <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Wade Wegner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 14:56:45 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.wadewegner.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mahalo a Aloha, Salesforce</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2021/01/mahalo-a-aloha-salesforce/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 14:56:45 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2021/01/mahalo-a-aloha-salesforce/</guid>
      <description>I never thought I’d be writing this blog post, yet here I am. After an incredible five years at Salesforce, it’s time to say “Mahalo a Aloha,” or thank you and goodbye.
I have so much gratitude for my colleagues at Salesforce, our customers, and of course, the fantastic Salesforce community. Never in my career have I felt the sense of mission that I have at Salesforce. The desire to advance the “state-of-the-art” for Salesforce developers was a passion reciprocated by my colleagues, supported by leadership, and always appreciated by our customers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Native Mobile App Using Salesforce DX and the Mobile SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2018/02/build-a-native-mobile-app-using-salesforce-dx-and-the-mobile-sdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2018/02/build-a-native-mobile-app-using-salesforce-dx-and-the-mobile-sdk/</guid>
      <description>This week I had the opportunity to demo how developers can combine project-based app development with Salesforce DX, the Salesforce CLI, Scratch Orgs, and the Mobile SDK to make &amp;ndash; at least, in my humble opinion &amp;ndash; a pretty compelling native app dev experience with Salesforce. In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll share some of the things I did with the hope that, after you look at it, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to try it out too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authenticate to your Scratch Orgs using the OAuth 2.0 JWT Bearer Flow</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2018/01/authenticate-to-your-scratch-orgs-using-the-oauth-2.0-jwt-bearer-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2018/01/authenticate-to-your-scratch-orgs-using-the-oauth-2.0-jwt-bearer-flow/</guid>
      <description>A different, if not more accurate or better, name for this blog post could be &amp;ldquo;Authenticate to a Scratch Org You Didn&amp;rsquo;t Create and Whose Password You Don&amp;rsquo;t Know.&amp;rdquo; I even went out to Twitter to ask for help and, well, Peter Churchill did not disappoint:
&amp;quot;I used JWT Bearer Flow with my Scratch Orgs and Dev Hub - you won&amp;#39;t believe what happened next!&amp;quot;
&amp;mdash; Peter Churchill (@britishboyindc) January 31, 2018  But, as you can see, I went the boring and conservative route.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Salesforce DX with Trailhead</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2018/01/using-salesforce-dx-with-trailhead/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2018/01/using-salesforce-dx-with-trailhead/</guid>
      <description>As you&amp;rsquo;ve likely seen on Twitter, I&amp;rsquo;ve really gotten into Trailhead these past few months. In particular, the Superbadges. I not only enjoy the challenge of working through the project, but regularly discover I don&amp;rsquo;t know nearly as much as I think I do. There&amp;rsquo;s a ton of useful and practical information in Trailead just waiting for us all to discover.
Of course, I have other motivations for doing Trailhead. I find it&amp;rsquo;s an amazing way to validate various workflows with Salesforce DX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy to Salesforce DX</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2017/09/deploy-to-salesforce-dx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2017/09/deploy-to-salesforce-dx/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re a Salesforce developer, it&amp;rsquo;s likely you&amp;rsquo;ve heard us talk about Salesforce DX these past months. (If not, you&amp;rsquo;re missing out and you should checkout the official documentation.) Since TrailheaDX, everyone has been able to use the new tools and services we&amp;rsquo;ve made available as part of the Salesforce DX beta. Personally, I&amp;rsquo;ve thoroughly enjoyed building all kinds of plugins for the Salesforce CLI.
 My primary plugin with lots of functionality: https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Workbench with your Scratch Org</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2017/04/use-workbench-with-your-scratch-org/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2017/04/use-workbench-with-your-scratch-org/</guid>
      <description>The Salesforce Workbench is a powerful set of tools for developers and admins to use with their org. You can easily describe, query, manipulate, and migrate data and metadata through the web browser, using a combination of Partner, Bulk, REST, Streaming, Metadata, and Tooling APIs. It&amp;rsquo;s completely open-sourced on Github by Ryan Brainard (@RyanBrainard).
And if all of this isn&amp;rsquo;t enough to convince you of its value, I can almost guarantee that Josh Kaplan (@JoshSfdx) is playing around in Workbench right now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Show the Salesforce DX Org Config in your Bash Prompt</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2017/04/show-the-salesforce-dx-org-config-in-your-bash-prompt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2017/04/show-the-salesforce-dx-org-config-in-your-bash-prompt/</guid>
      <description>Using the capabilities of Salesforce DX you can enable some neat tricks. Such as displaying your org configuration in your Bash prompt:
But, first, a little background &amp;hellip;
The Salesforce DX CLI provides some powerful capabilities for tracking your Salesforce org. When you login with sfdx force:auth:web:login (-a &amp;lt;alias&amp;gt; lets you alias the org) your credentials are encrypted and stored locally. When running subsequent commands, you can append -u &amp;lt;username|alias&amp;gt; to the command to target an org.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the OAuth 2.0 JWT Bearer Flow to Support the Salesforce DX CLI</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2017/04/using-the-oauth-2.0-jwt-bearer-flow-to-support-the-salesforce-dx-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2017/04/using-the-oauth-2.0-jwt-bearer-flow-to-support-the-salesforce-dx-cli/</guid>
      <description>The Salesforce DX (SFDX) CLI makes it easy to run commands as a developer. It also makes it really easy to create scripts that facilitate automation. A great example is the following tweet from Pat Patterson:
#SalesforceDX is awesome! I can create a scratch org for testing from a bash script. Great job, @WadeWegner &amp;amp; team! pic.twitter.com/Nu3yI2UQH0
&amp;mdash; Pat Patterson (@metadaddy) March 29, 2017  The praise for SFDX is awesome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Plugin for the Salesforce CLI</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2017/03/creating-a-plugin-for-the-salesforce-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2017/03/creating-a-plugin-for-the-salesforce-cli/</guid>
      <description>This post is valid for the Salesforce DX (SFDX) pilot. Please note that details may change and I&amp;rsquo;ll do my best to update accordingly.
Recently I highlighted a neat way to use open source software with Salesforce DX. Since then I&amp;rsquo;ve used Appiphony&amp;rsquo;s custom base components many, many times in demos and apps I&amp;rsquo;ve built.
It didn&amp;rsquo;t take long for me to get tired of removing the Git details when pulling the OSS from Github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salesforce DX Strike</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2017/03/salesforce-dx-strike/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2017/03/salesforce-dx-strike/</guid>
      <description>Like many people at Salesforce and in the community, I was really excited and impressed to see Lightning Strike by Appiphony. Not to take away from the remarkable tool they built to visually explore and configure Lightning components, I was most excited by the custom Lightning Components they built and released to the community through their Github repository Strike-Components.
Immediately I wanted to try these components out myself. And fortunate, using Salesforce DX, it&amp;rsquo;s really quite easy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salesforce DX Pilot Demos</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2017/02/salesforce-dx-pilot-demos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2017/02/salesforce-dx-pilot-demos/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re so excited to have recently launched the Salesforce DX pilot. Our teams have been hard at work on Salesforce DX, and it&amp;rsquo;s tremendously exciting to have so many of you using the tools and trying out an entirely new way to build applications on the Salesforce platform.
I thought it would be helpful to share with everyone the demos from the Salesforce DX pilot kickoff webinar. This is cut directly from the webinar, so apologies for any rough edges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Go Site Extension and Resource Template for Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2015/01/creating-a-go-site-extension-and-resource-template-for-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2015/01/creating-a-go-site-extension-and-resource-template-for-azure/</guid>
      <description>The New Year is a good time to set goals for yourself. I&amp;rsquo;ve challenged myself this year to explore and ship some apps using the Go language, which is likely no surprise given my recent posts on setting up Go on Windows and running Go on Azure Websites.
As part of my initial explorations, I used Azure Websites to host my Go web apps. The last post I wrote showed my first Go prototype on Azure Websites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 Simple Steps to Run Go Language in Azure Websites</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/12/4-simple-steps-to-run-go-language-in-azure-websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/12/4-simple-steps-to-run-go-language-in-azure-websites/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago I wrote a GoLang web app and wanted to find a good place to host it. Given I work with the team that builds Azure Websites, it seemed only fitting to host it in Azure Websites. Turns out, it works great! However, there aren&amp;rsquo;t any resources available that walk you through the steps. Consequently, I wrote the following tutorial.
(Incidentally, if you want to start to use Go Language and run Windows you&amp;rsquo;ll want to review my post Easy Go Programming Setup for Windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy Go Programming Setup for Windows</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/12/easy-go-programming-setup-for-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/12/easy-go-programming-setup-for-windows/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had to do this more than once recently, so I figured I&amp;rsquo;d document the simple steps for setting up the Go programming language on Windows. Most of this is simple and straightforward. The only tricky part I found is setting up your GOPATH, which defines a convention for storing and building Go code you write and acquire from open source code repositories.
5 Simple Steps Follow these five simple steps to install Go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Windows 8 App for Salesforce With No Code Using Project Siena</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/08/build-a-windows-8-app-for-salesforce-with-no-code-using-project-siena/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/08/build-a-windows-8-app-for-salesforce-with-no-code-using-project-siena/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft Project Siena (Beta) is a tool that allows a business user (i.e. non-developer) to quickly building rich business applications for Windows 8. You can learn all about the tool on the Microsoft Project Siena web site and by watching a set of tutorials on the Microsoft Project Siena (Beta) Channel 9 Blog.
Having recently left Salesforce to join Microsoft, I was curious about how to build a Project Siena app that integrated into Salesforce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create an iBeacon Transmitter with the Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/05/create-an-ibeacon-transmitter-with-the-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/05/create-an-ibeacon-transmitter-with-the-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>iBeacon is the Apple trademark for a low-powered, low-cost transmitter that can notify nearby iOS 7 devices of its presence. It uses Bluetooth Low Energy (BLE), also called Bluetooth Smart, technology to transmit an advertisement that includes a universally unique identifier (UUID). Android devices can receive iBeacon advertisements and, fortunately for those of us who like to hack around, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t take too much work to setup a Raspberry Pi to emit iBeacon advertisements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salesforce Did What? How We Built the Salesforce Toolkits for .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/05/salesforce-did-what-how-we-built-the-salesforce-toolkits-for-.net/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/05/salesforce-did-what-how-we-built-the-salesforce-toolkits-for-.net/</guid>
      <description>I had the great pleasure this week to speak at TechEd North America 2014 on how we built the Salesforce Toolkits for .NET. It was a blast, and I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprised if I was the first Salesforce employee to speak at TechEd. Many thanks to my friends at Microsoft for the opportunity.
Here is the video recording of the talk on Channel 9:
 The highlight of the talk for me was that, rather than explain through slides, I built a brand new SDK during the talk and committed it live to Github in this repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uploading an Attachment to Salesforce with the SOAP and REST APIs</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/05/uploading-an-attachment-to-salesforce-with-the-soap-and-rest-apis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/05/uploading-an-attachment-to-salesforce-with-the-soap-and-rest-apis/</guid>
      <description>Earlier today a colleague asked me if I had an example of using Python to create an attachment in Salesforce. I didn&amp;rsquo;t, but that didn&amp;rsquo;t stop me from creating a couple. Sadly, our documentation here isn&amp;rsquo;t the greatest. You can look at the Insert or Update Blob Data for the REST API or Attachment for our SOAP API. If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, neither document is good enough; I had to continue to dig around to figure out exactly what I needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update Records with Python and the Salesforce Bulk API</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/04/update-records-with-python-and-the-salesforce-bulk-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/04/update-records-with-python-and-the-salesforce-bulk-api/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s time to take a little break from .NET and enjoy the many different programming languages you can use when integrating to the Salesforce1 Platform. But first, a public service announcement from Steve Marx:
 This week a colleague of mine asked me if I could help him by writing a script to update data he has in Salesforce (okay, he asked me weeks ago, and I only got to it yesterday).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Salesforce Accelerators for Windows Store Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/04/announcing-the-salesforce-accelerators-for-windows-store-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/04/announcing-the-salesforce-accelerators-for-windows-store-apps/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I was pleased to announce the Salesforce Accelerators for Windows Phone 8 Apps. Today I&amp;rsquo;m excited to tell you about the Salesforce Accelerators for Windows Store Apps:
 DeveloperForce.Windows8.Login DeveloperForce.Windows8.Samples.Accounts  These accelerators exist to make it easier for you to get started building Windows 8 store apps and work directly with the Salesforce Toolkits for .NET. Take a look at this short video to see just how easy it is to get started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Salesforce Accelerators for Windows Phone 8 Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/04/announcing-the-salesforce-accelerators-for-windows-phone-8-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/04/announcing-the-salesforce-accelerators-for-windows-phone-8-apps/</guid>
      <description>I am pleased to announce the Salesforce Accelerators for Windows Phone 8 Apps, a set of assets designed to make it easier to create new applications using the Salesforce Toolkits for .NET:
 DeveloperForce.WindowsPhone8.Login DeveloperForce.WindowsPhone8.Samples.Accounts  The Salesforce Toolkits for .NET, released earlier this year, allow you to interact with the Force.com and Chatter REST APIs using native .NET code on multiple platforms and devices. Many developers and companies have already benefited from these libraries and have built new ASP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a Custom Object with .NET using the Force.com Metadata API ... and No Proxy Classes!</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/03/create-a-custom-object-with-.net-using-the-force.com-metadata-api-...-and-no-proxy-classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/03/create-a-custom-object-with-.net-using-the-force.com-metadata-api-...-and-no-proxy-classes/</guid>
      <description>Update 2/24/14
Over the weekend I took much of what I wrote below and packaged it up in a NuGet package. You can use the NuGet to accomplish everything I wrote below with fewer lines of code. Full details are available on the WadeWegner.Salesforce.SOAPHelpers Github repository and you can get the NuGet package with the following command:
 Install-Package WadeWegner.Salesforce.SOAPHelpers
Enjoy!
Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve written a lot about using the Force.com REST API with .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Send a Text Message to Your IoT Thermal Printer? No Problem. (And Print Your Lunch Menu Too!)</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/02/send-a-text-message-to-your-iot-thermal-printer-no-problem.-and-print-your-lunch-menu-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/02/send-a-text-message-to-your-iot-thermal-printer-no-problem.-and-print-your-lunch-menu-too/</guid>
      <description>How do you send a text message from your phone and have it print on a thermal printer that&amp;rsquo;s sitting on your kitchen counter?
Hang on, we&amp;rsquo;ll get to that shortly!
Shortly after Dreamforce last year I was turned on to Adafruit Industries by my teammate Reid Carlberg. I&amp;rsquo;ve since built a number of cool little gadgets, including the Brain Machine and the TV B Gone. Both projects were a ton of fun and a great way to get started with soldering and simple circuitry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support for Refresh Tokens, Async Suffix, and Updated Sample Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/02/support-for-refresh-tokens-async-suffix-and-updated-sample-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/02/support-for-refresh-tokens-async-suffix-and-updated-sample-apps/</guid>
      <description>Over the past two days I&amp;rsquo;ve committed and published a number of updates to the Salesforce Toolkits for .NET worth sharing. But first, a special thanks to Rocky Assad and Delmer Johnson for the contributions they have made to the toolkits over the past couple weeks. It&amp;rsquo;s fantastic to see such passionate involvement from members of the Salesforce developer community!
There are three updates I&amp;rsquo;d like to discuss in this post:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the WebAuthenticationBroker for Salesforce Authentication on Windows 8</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/01/using-the-webauthenticationbroker-for-salesforce-authentication-on-windows-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/01/using-the-webauthenticationbroker-for-salesforce-authentication-on-windows-8/</guid>
      <description>Two days ago I published a sample app for Windows Phone 8 that demonstrates how to authenticate users and make calls against the Force.com REST API using the Salesforce Toolkits for .NET. The next obvious step was to build a sample application for Windows 8. ACHIEVEMENT UNLOCKED!
You can get the sample here: https://github.com/developerforce/Force.com-Toolkit-for-NET/tree/master/samples/Windows8OAuth.
To get authentication working in Windows 8 we&amp;rsquo;ll use the WebAuthenticationBroker, which manages the asynchronous authentication operation in a modal dialog window.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting to Salesforce from a Windows Phone 8 App</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/01/connecting-to-salesforce-from-a-windows-phone-8-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/01/connecting-to-salesforce-from-a-windows-phone-8-app/</guid>
      <description>One of the top requests I&amp;rsquo;ve received since releasing the Salesforce Toolkits for .NET has been a Windows Phone 8 sample application. I was very happy to oblige and today I&amp;rsquo;m pleased to share with you the Windows Phone 8 OAuth sample application. This sample makes use of the Developerforce.Force and Developerforce.Common NuGet packages. Since the .NET libraries in the toolkits are all portable class libraries developers are able to build applications targeting .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better Support for HttpClient in the Salesforce Toolkits for .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/01/better-support-for-httpclient-in-the-salesforce-toolkits-for-.net/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/01/better-support-for-httpclient-in-the-salesforce-toolkits-for-.net/</guid>
      <description>If you follow me on Twitter, chances are you heard we released a set of Salesforce Toolkits for .NET last week. The reception has been extraordinary, and I&amp;rsquo;m so excited to see the applications developers build using these toolkits!
Take a look at the various annoucements and posts:
  Wade Wegner: Announcing the Salesforce Toolkits for .NET
  Developer Force Team Blog: Announcing the Salesforce Toolkits for .NET</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Salesforce Toolkits for .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/01/announcing-the-salesforce-toolkits-for-.net/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/01/announcing-the-salesforce-toolkits-for-.net/</guid>
      <description>I am extremely pleased to announce the availability of two Salesforce Toolkits for .NET developers: the Force.com Toolkit for .NET and the Chatter Toolkit for .NET. These toolkits provide an easy way for .NET developers to interact with the Force.com and Chatter REST APIs using a native .NET libraries.
The easiest way to get started is to use the NuGet packages:
 Install-Package DeveloperForce.Force
Install-Package DeveloperForce.Chatter
You can find a set of API examples and samples in the Github repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write Unit Tests to Check Your HTTP Headers (and Other HTTP Request Stuff) in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/01/how-to-write-unit-tests-to-check-your-http-headers-and-other-http-request-stuff-in-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2014/01/how-to-write-unit-tests-to-check-your-http-headers-and-other-http-request-stuff-in-c/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been building a set of libraries recently that make HTTP calls into the Force.com and Chatter REST APIs and I needed to find a way to test my methods and ensure that my HTTP Requests were constructed correctly. These libraries do a number of things to help make valid HTTP calls; any inadvertant changes (or introduced bugs) could cause a lot of problems. Fortunately, with help from Ryan Dunn, I was able to build some unit tests that are able to inspect my HttpRequestMessage an ensure that everything has been properly setup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salesforce1 Tutorial for the Dreamforce &#39;13 Developer Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2013/12/salesforce1-tutorial-for-the-dreamforce-13-developer-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2013/12/salesforce1-tutorial-for-the-dreamforce-13-developer-keynote/</guid>
      <description>We just released a Salesforce1 tutorial on Github that walks you though the same demo presented by Dave Carroll at the Dreamforce &amp;lsquo;13 Developer&amp;rsquo;s Keynote.
This tutorial enables you to do the following with Salesforce1:
 Use the Force Command-Line Interface (CLI) tool to manipulate metadata in Salesforce. Create a Salesforce1 mobile application using the Salesforce1 app container. Create Visualforce components and pages enabled for the Salesforce1 mobile application. Use mobile cards and create publisher actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Simple Lua Script Token Request with Webscript.io</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2013/11/a-simple-lua-script-token-request-with-webscript.io/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2013/11/a-simple-lua-script-token-request-with-webscript.io/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I spent some time writing a Python token request script against the Force.com APIs. Today I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share a short code snippet for doing the same thing but this time using Lua.
Why Lua? Why not!
No, I have a good reason for getting this to work in Lua. I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of Webscript.io which provides a tremendously simple way to create web APIs. Webscripts are all written in Lua.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Force.com Token Requests with Python</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2013/11/force.com-token-requests-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2013/11/force.com-token-requests-with-python/</guid>
      <description>Today I wrote some Python code for querying the Force.com REST APIs. It started pretty straightforward but I stumbled upon an important concept when I tried to run this Python from an untrusted location. More on this in a moment. Let&amp;rsquo;s start at the beginning.
You first need to create a Connected App.
A connected app is an application that integrates with salesforce.com using APIs and uses either SAML and OAuth protocols to authenticate, provide Single Sign-On, and provide tokens for use with Salesforce APIs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Command-line Interface for Force.com</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2013/11/a-command-line-interface-for-force.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2013/11/a-command-line-interface-for-force.com/</guid>
      <description>Released this week at Dreamforce is a new command-line interface (CLI) tool for Force.com. This tool is open-sourced and available at http://github.com/heroku/force. This tool lets you quickly interact with the Force.com APIs and opens up interesting opportunities for scripting and automating tasks on Force.com.
You can immediately download the precompiled binaries for the force command-line interface and start using it today:
 Linux: 32-bit | 64-bit OS X: 32-bit | 64-bit Windows: 32-bit | 64-bit  Simply download the binary and run it from the command-line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing for the Salesforce $1 Million Hackathon</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2013/11/preparing-for-the-salesforce-1-million-hackathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2013/11/preparing-for-the-salesforce-1-million-hackathon/</guid>
      <description>This post originally appeared on the Salesforce Developer Relations blog on November 12, 2013.
As you prepare to build a mobile app for the Salesforce $1 Million Hackathon next week, it may help to step back and reflect on the capabilities of the Salesforce Platform and how tapping into these capabilities will better enable you to compete. In particular, it will help to understand why, and how, access to rich customer data can give your application an edge – in both the hackathon and beyond.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joining Salesforce</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2013/11/joining-salesforce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2013/11/joining-salesforce/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this year I started an incubation project at Aditi Technologies to explore Salesforce as a platform for building cloud applications. Today I start at Salesforce as a full-time employee.
Life is funny sometimes, no?
When I left Microsoft I did so to take a shot at building products and applications for Windows Azure. I&amp;rsquo;ve done that, and more. I hadn’t planned on leaving Aditi any time soon but there are some opportunities too awesome to ignore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring the Force.com IDE with Eclipse and Using Git</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2013/10/configuring-the-force.com-ide-with-eclipse-and-using-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2013/10/configuring-the-force.com-ide-with-eclipse-and-using-git/</guid>
      <description>Today I needed to configure Eclipse to use the Force.COM IDE. In the past I&amp;rsquo;ve edited Apex and Visualforce code either directly inline &amp;hellip;
&amp;hellip; or using the Developer Console. Both are decent for quick and dirty updates, but when it comes to applying best practices (i.e. automated builds, source control, and so forth) I don&amp;rsquo;t want to live in the browser.
There&amp;rsquo;s a good wiki article available on the Developer Force website which explains how to setup Eclipse with the Force.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrated to Jekyll</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2013/10/migrated-to-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2013/10/migrated-to-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>For quite some time I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to move my blog off WordPress and start to use Jekyll - in fact, I started looking into Jekyll back when I was still at Microsoft and had many conversations with Steve Marx about making the move. In this short post I want to discuss my motivations for making the switch and also highlight some of the unique things I did to make this quick and simple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell Script for Cleaning Up Your Windows Azure Resources</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2013/10/powershell-script-for-cleaning-up-your-windows-azure-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2013/10/powershell-script-for-cleaning-up-your-windows-azure-resources/</guid>
      <description>Special thanks to Michael Washam for helping me find and fix a bug in my code!
 I find myself regularly creating resources in Windows Azure, such as cloud services, virtual machines, storage accounts, virtual networks, and the like. Most of the time this is part of writing scripts or testing out deployments, and I don&amp;rsquo;t plan to keep them around indefinitely. The challenge this creates is how to cleanup all these resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Anonymous Apex REST APIs with Force.com</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2013/03/creating-anonymous-apex-rest-apis-with-force.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 21:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2013/03/creating-anonymous-apex-rest-apis-with-force.com/</guid>
      <description>The Force.com REST API lets you integration with Force.com applications using standard HTTP methods. This API provides a way to expose the data you have within your Force.com application to external applications – both mobile and non-mobile. A few useful bits of information related to these REST APIs:
 Use standard HTTP verbs: GET, POST, PUT, PATCH, DELETE, and HEAD. You can use either HTTP or HTTPS. Use standard security to authenticate your REST calls via OAuth 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Few Tips on Getting Started with Force.com</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2013/03/a-few-tips-on-getting-started-with-force.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2013/03/a-few-tips-on-getting-started-with-force.com/</guid>
      <description>Today I got the opportunity to attend a Salesforce.com “hack day” in San Francisco. Quite fun, and I learned a lot from Adam Seligman, Dave Carroll, Pat Patterson, and Akhilesh Gupta. This is a great team: extremely personable, clearly excited about their platform and the technology, and willing to pull up their sleeves and write some code. My kind of people.
During the hack day I acquired a few tips for getting started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To The Cloud(s)</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2013/03/to-the-clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 16:26:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2013/03/to-the-clouds/</guid>
      <description>One of my goals this past year has been to get more hands-on with respects to real-world cloud applications. Working for Aditi has provided many opportunities to dig into some interesting cloud workloads. In addition to building all kinds of applications running in Windows Azure, I’ve learned a lot working with Ryan Dunn and Raghu Rajagopalan on building products (like Scheduler) that run in the cloud.
Coming from a Windows Azure focus at Microsoft my natural tendency has been to approach most problems with solutions in Windows Azure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Windows Azure Virtual Machines to Publish and Synchronize a Web Farm</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2013/03/using-windows-azure-virtual-machines-to-publish-and-synchronize-a-web-farm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 04:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2013/03/using-windows-azure-virtual-machines-to-publish-and-synchronize-a-web-farm/</guid>
      <description>Lately I’ve been attempting to try out a number of different techniques for publishing web applications – both websites and web APIs – to the cloud. I’m being purposely vague when saying “the cloud” – it could be Windows Azure, AWS, or even a traditional hosting provider. It’s likely you saw a great post by Michael Washam that provides a solution for using Windows Azure virtual machines along with Web Deploy and a few PowerShell scripts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detecting Expired PKI Certificates</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2013/02/detecting-expired-pki-certificates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2013 19:06:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2013/02/detecting-expired-pki-certificates/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday Windows Azure experienced a worldwide disruption in many services due to an expired PKI certificate for Windows Azure storage. Mary Jo Foley’s article Windows Azure storage issue: Expired HTTPS certificate possibly at fault provides the best coverage of the event as it unfolded. You can also take a look at a few threads on the Windows Azure forum and Stack Overflow that provide a lot of commentary on the event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting the Application ID and Hardware ID in Windows Store Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2012/09/getting-the-application-id-and-hardware-id-in-windows-store-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2012 22:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2012/09/getting-the-application-id-and-hardware-id-in-windows-store-applications/</guid>
      <description>So far I’ve really enjoyed developing applications for Windows 8. I still can’t claim to be particularly good at XAML design work yet, but I’m getting the hang of Windows Store Apps in C# using Windows RT. That said, there are have been a number of times when I’ve been lost and had to hit MSDN and search engines in order to figure things out. What makes this particularly challenging is that much of the information you’ll find is old and not appropriate for Windows 8 RTM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating C# Classes from JSON</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2012/08/generating-c#-classes-from-json/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2012 13:15:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2012/08/generating-c#-classes-from-json/</guid>
      <description>I’ve long advocated using JSON when building mobile and cloud applications. If nothing else, the payload size makes it extremely efficient when transferred over the wire – take a look at the size of the same information formatted as OData, REST-XML, and lastly JSON:
Pretty compelling.
Despite the use of JSON – and great frameworks like JSON.NET and SimpleJson – I always struggled with creating my C# classes when working with an existing web service that returned JSON.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from the MEET Windows Azure Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2012/06/notes-from-the-meet-windows-azure-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2012 21:35:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2012/06/notes-from-the-meet-windows-azure-keynote/</guid>
      <description>Excellent keynote today by Scott Guthrie and the Windows Azure team! I don’t know if it’s because I’m seeing it on the other side for the first time or if it’s due to the amazing new capabilities introduced into Windows Azure, but I loved every second of it! Within a few minutes Scott had jumped into a demo and it was nonstop thereafter!
I’ve been waiting for almost a year to write this blog post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early Thoughts on the Windows Azure Announcements</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2012/06/early-thoughts-on-the-windows-azure-announcements/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2012 16:43:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2012/06/early-thoughts-on-the-windows-azure-announcements/</guid>
      <description>Today’s release marks a significant milestone for Windows Azure. To date, Windows Azure has been a platform that allows developers to build and run applications across Microsoft’s global datacenters – the key emphasis has been on “applications”. Windows Azure has not been a platform for providing the underlying infrastructure for running your own virtual machine – this has been a key pain point for many customers looking to move to the cloud that Microsoft has heard loud and clear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Capped Exponential Back-Off for Queues</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2012/04/simple-capped-exponential-back-off-for-queues/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 21:15:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2012/04/simple-capped-exponential-back-off-for-queues/</guid>
      <description>Recently Steve Marx and I spent a few hours working on a best practices document for Windows Azure. As expected, this was a fun and educational experience – plenty of goofing around, but also some really good discussion on things to think about when building applications for Windows Azure. One of the items we discussed is a better approach for sleeping inside the Worker Role when pulling from queues. Rather than defaulting to a retry every 10 seconds we decided that the best approach is to exponentially back-off on your queue reads while capping it with an upper bound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Return Empty Set Instead of ResourceNotFound from Table Storage</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2012/04/return-empty-set-instead-of-resourcenotfound-from-table-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2012 21:50:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2012/04/return-empty-set-instead-of-resourcenotfound-from-table-storage/</guid>
      <description>This past week I’ve been working on a little project – amazing how less email equates to more time for other endeavors – and I was surprised when I received a DataServiceQueryException when querying table storage in the local storage emulator. I was querying based on partition and row keys and, if no data matched the statement, I received an HTTP 404: Resource Not Found exception.
I was initially puzzled. Shouldn’t I receive an empty set or null instead?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joining Aditi Technologies as Chief Technology Officer</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2012/04/joining-aditi-technologies-as-chief-technology-officer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 14:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2012/04/joining-aditi-technologies-as-chief-technology-officer/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a little more than three weeks since I announced my departure from Microsoft. Leaving Microsoft was harder than I expected and I never anticipated the outpouring of support and appreciation from everyone. From the bottom of my heart, thank you!
Today I’m really excited to share that I’ve joined Aditi Technologies as Chief Technology Officer. Aditi is a top Microsoft partner with a lot of talented people and has recently made a lot of key investments – particularly around Windows Azure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaving Microsoft</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2012/03/leaving-microsoft/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2012 15:05:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2012/03/leaving-microsoft/</guid>
      <description>I’ve spent a fair amount of time thinking about the right title for this post. Steve Marx was clever with Career vNext, Sriram Krishnan waxed poetic with On Leaving Microsoft, and Brad Abrams just came out and talked about My Last Day at Microsoft. Yet no matter how it’s phrased it comes down to one thing: leaving Microsoft.
I can honestly say that I never thought this day would come. Working for Microsoft has been a dream come true – brilliant colleagues, interesting opportunities, and inspiring technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cannot create database &#39;DevelopmentStorageDb20110816&#39; for the Windows Azure Storage Emulator</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2012/01/cannot-create-database-developmentstoragedb20110816-for-the-windows-azure-storage-emulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2012 18:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2012/01/cannot-create-database-developmentstoragedb20110816-for-the-windows-azure-storage-emulator/</guid>
      <description>Have you seen this error before? If you’ve spent any time with the Windows Azure storage emulator it’s highly probable. Here’s the full text:
Added reservation for http://127.0.0.1:10000/ in user account COMPUTER\User. Added reservation for http://127.0.0.1:10001/ in user account COMPUTER\User. Added reservation for http://127.0.0.1:10002/ in user account COMPUTER\User. Creating database DevelopmentStorageDb20110816... Cannot create database &#39;DevelopmentStorageDb20110816&#39; : CREATE DATABASE permission denied in database &#39;master&#39;. One or more initialization actions have failed. Resolve these errors before attempting to run the storage emulator again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are You Building Mobile &#43; Cloud Applications? Tell Me!</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2012/01/are-you-building-mobile-cloud-applications-tell-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2012 19:02:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2012/01/are-you-building-mobile-cloud-applications-tell-me/</guid>
      <description>If you follow my blog or on Twitter then you know that I’m passionate about using services running in Windows Azure to power mobile applications. To effectively run mobile services for mobile apps you need a platform that is responsive to a global audience and able to scale to the needs of your user base – Windows Azure provides these capabilities.
As part of the refresh of the WindowsAzure.com we have also provided additional information about mobile scenarios – it’s worth taking a look.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Handle a Faulted Channel with the Windows Azure Service Bus</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/12/how-to-handle-a-faulted-channel-with-the-windows-azure-service-bus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2011 04:52:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/12/how-to-handle-a-faulted-channel-with-the-windows-azure-service-bus/</guid>
      <description>Recently I wrote a WCF service that fronted an on-premises SQL Server database for an MVC application running in a Window Azure Web Role. There are a number of ways I could have approached this scenario; I decided to use the netTcpRelayBinding via the Windows Azure Service Bus for the following reasons:
  I needed optimal performance (i.e. TCP over HTTP).
  I wanted to reuse existing connections (rather than opening many connections).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unable to find assembly references that are compatible with the target framework &#39;Silverlight,Version=v4.0, Profile=WindowsPhone71&#39;</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/11/unable-to-find-assembly-references-that-are-compatible-with-the-target-framework-silverlightversionv4.0-profilewindowsphone71/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 18:18:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/11/unable-to-find-assembly-references-that-are-compatible-with-the-target-framework-silverlightversionv4.0-profilewindowsphone71/</guid>
      <description>Yes, that title is a mouthful. But this title is as cryptic as the error that can get generated when trying to install a NuGet package:
Install-Package : Unable to find assembly references that are compatible with the target framework &#39;Silverlight,Version=v4.0,Profile=WindowsPhone71&#39;. At line:1 char:16 + Install-Package &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt; Phone.Storage + CategoryInfo : NotSpecified: (:) [Install-Package], InvalidOperationException + FullyQualifiedErrorId : NuGetCmdletUnhandledException, NuGet.PowerShell.Commands.InstallPackageCommand  Here’s what you’ll see in Visual Studio:
This is the error I get when trying to install one of our NuGet packages on a freshly built machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Push Notification Support to Your Windows Phone Application</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/11/adding-push-notification-support-to-your-windows-phone-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2011 22:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/11/adding-push-notification-support-to-your-windows-phone-application/</guid>
      <description>A couple days ago I wrote a post on outsourcing user authentication in a Windows Phone application, demonstrating how easy it is to leverage the Windows Azure Access Control service in your Windows Phone application. The solution is built using a set of NuGet packages that our team has built for Windows Phone + Windows Azure – they provide a similar development experience by allowing you to better manage dependencies and compose great application experiences on the Windows Phone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outsourcing User Authentication in a Windows Phone Application</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/11/outsourcing-user-authentication-in-a-windows-phone-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2011 05:18:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/11/outsourcing-user-authentication-in-a-windows-phone-application/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I shared all the NuGet packages we’re building to make it easy to build Windows Phone and Windows Azure applications. Today I wanted to share how easy it is to build a Windows Phone application that leverages the Windows Azure Access Control service.
The Phone.Identity.AccessControl.BasePage NuGet package includes a control for Window Phone that allows your phone applications to outsource user authentication to the Windows Azure Access Control service (ACS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programmatically Installing and Using Your Management Certificate with the New .publishsettings File</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/11/programmatically-installing-and-using-your-management-certificate-with-the-new-.publishsettings-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2011 21:11:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/11/programmatically-installing-and-using-your-management-certificate-with-the-new-.publishsettings-file/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this week we released the Windows Azure SDK 1.6, which includes a lot of great updates to the emulators, tools for Visual Studio, and libraries. One of my favorite additions is a new way to get a management certificate installed into Windows Azure and onto your machine. You can now browse to https://windows.azure.com/download/publishprofile.aspx and login with your Live ID; this process will do two things:
  Generate a management certificate that is installed into Windows Azures on your behalf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NuGet Packages for Windows Azure and Windows Phone Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/11/nuget-packages-for-windows-azure-and-windows-phone-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2011 22:21:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/11/nuget-packages-for-windows-azure-and-windows-phone-developers/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve been paying attention to the Windows Azure Toolkit for Windows Phone (or my twitter feed) the last couple weeks, you’ve probably noticed something about NuGet packages. We’ve been building a lot of Windows Phone and Windows Azure NuGet packages that, when composed together, give you the ability to quickly build some cool applications. To highlight this, here’s a short video that shows how you can enable push notification support in a brand new Windows Phone 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aggregating RSS Feeds in C# and ASP.NET MVC 3</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/11/aggregating-rss-feeds-in-c#-and-asp.net-mvc-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2011 19:48:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/11/aggregating-rss-feeds-in-c#-and-asp.net-mvc-3/</guid>
      <description>I’m working on a Windows Phone project that requires me to surface up multiple RSS feeds as a single source. I needed a way to do this quickly and easily, and with a little help from friends on Twitter (particularly a suggestion from @bertcraven) I found a nice way to accomplish this using the SyndicationFeed in System.ServiceModel.Syndication.
I’ve detailed the steps below, but if you want to get to the heart of it then here’s the code to get this working:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Azure Platform Training Kit - October Release</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/10/windows-azure-platform-training-kit-october-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2011 21:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/10/windows-azure-platform-training-kit-october-release/</guid>
      <description>Today we published the Windows Azure Platform Training Kit - October Release. The Windows Azure Platform Training Kit includes hands-on labs, presentations, and samples to help you understand how to build applications that utilize Windows Azure, SQL Azure, and the Windows Azure AppFabric.
  Download Now: You can download the full training kit including the hands-on labs, demo scripts, and presentations from the Microsoft download center here: http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=130354.
  Browse the hands-on labs: Alternatively, you can browse through the individual hands-on labs on the MSDN site here: http://bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Azure Toolkit for Windows Phone v1.3.1</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/10/windows-azure-toolkit-for-windows-phone-v1.3.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 22:22:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/10/windows-azure-toolkit-for-windows-phone-v1.3.1/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I released an update to the Windows Azure Toolkit for Windows Phone. There are a few important updates in this release, so I encourage you to go and download the new tools. We have a number of significant updates:
  Upgraded Windows Azure projects to Windows Azure Tools for Microsoft Visual Studio 2010 1.5 – September 2011
  Upgraded the tools tools to support the Windows Phone Developer Tools RTW</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Azure Platform Training Kit, September 2011 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/09/windows-azure-platform-training-kit-september-2011-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2011 15:38:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/09/windows-azure-platform-training-kit-september-2011-release/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday we released the Window Azure Platform Training Kit – September 2011 Release. You can get the content here:
  Windows Azure Platform Training Kit (offline)
  Windows Azure Platform Training Courses (online)
  The September 2011 release of the training kit includes the following updates:
  [New Hands-On Lab] Service Bus Messaging
  [Updated] Labs and Demos to leverage the new Window Azure SDK &amp;amp; Tools 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running the Windows Azure Tools &amp;amp; SDK on the Windows Developer Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/09/running-the-windows-azure-tools-amp-sdk-on-the-windows-developer-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2011 06:52:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/09/running-the-windows-azure-tools-amp-sdk-on-the-windows-developer-preview/</guid>
      <description>Now that we can get our hands on the Windows Developer Preview of Windows 8, I’m sure everyone is excited to start building applications! For many of us, this means that we’ll want to install all of the great Windows Azure tools on our Windows Developer Preview machine – especially if we plan to take advantage of the new Windows Azure Toolkit for Windows 8. However, there are a few things we’ll need to do in order to get things to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metro Style Apps with Windows Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/09/metro-style-apps-with-windows-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2011 17:53:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/09/metro-style-apps-with-windows-azure/</guid>
      <description>I love building keynote applications! I had the great fortune to work with John Shewchuk – Technical Fellow at Microsoft – as he demonstrated a vision for how identity in Windows Azure can enable great experiences in Windows 8. I wanted to quickly provide some background on the components of the sample application he showed called Margie’s Travel.
Margie’s Travel is a sample travel application that demonstrates how you can track and manage your trips across multiple Windows 8 machines using a combination of technologies in Windows Azure and Windows 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Azure Toolkits for Devices - Now With Android!</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/08/windows-azure-toolkits-for-devices-now-with-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 15:29:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/08/windows-azure-toolkits-for-devices-now-with-android/</guid>
      <description>I am **_tremendously _**pleased to share that today we have released the Windows Azure Toolkit for Android! We announced our intentions to build a toolkit for Android back in May, and it had always been our intention to release this summer (we only missed by a week or so).
In addition to this release of Android, we have also:
  Released the Windows Azure Toolkit for Windows Phone (v1.3.0)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using ELMAH in Windows Azure with Table Storage</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/08/using-elmah-in-windows-azure-with-table-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2011 03:34:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/08/using-elmah-in-windows-azure-with-table-storage/</guid>
      <description>In this week’s episode of Cloud Cover, Steve and I covered Logging, Tracing, and ELMAH in Windows Azure. Steve explored the first two topics while I looked into ELMAH in Windows Azure. You should make sure and take a look at his posts – they’re useful:
  Printf(“HERE”) in the Cloud
  Lightweight Tracing to Windows Azure Tables
  ELMAH (Error Logging Modules and Handlers) itself is extremely useful, and with a few simple modifications can provide a very effective way to handle application-wide error logging for your ASP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Windows Azure Marketplace for Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/08/introduction-to-windows-azure-marketplace-for-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2011 04:06:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/08/introduction-to-windows-azure-marketplace-for-applications/</guid>
      <description>Today we released an update to the Windows Azure Platform Training Kit to include a new HOL: Introduction to Windows Azure Marketplace for Applications. You can download the updated Windows Azure Platform Training Kit – August 2011 Refresh from download center or view online now on the Windows Azure Platform Training Course on MSDN.
The important take away is that in this HOL you will take an application through the full provisioning process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WA Toolkit for iOS: New Project Experience with Windows Azure Access Control Service</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/08/wa-toolkit-for-ios-new-project-experience-with-windows-azure-access-control-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 23:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/08/wa-toolkit-for-ios-new-project-experience-with-windows-azure-access-control-service/</guid>
      <description>The v1.2 release of the Windows Azure Toolkit for iOS includes support for Windows Azure Access Control Service (ACS). The enables iOS developers to create applications that can use and rely on federated identity providers such as Windows Live, Google Accounts, and Facebook Connect.
This walkthrough document covers configuring the ACS service and creating a new iOS project using XCode to authenticate against this service. This is accomplished using the following three steps in this document:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WA Toolkit for iOS: New Project Experience for Accessing Windows Azure Storage</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/08/wa-toolkit-for-ios-new-project-experience-for-accessing-windows-azure-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 22:15:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/08/wa-toolkit-for-ios-new-project-experience-for-accessing-windows-azure-storage/</guid>
      <description>The Windows Azure Toolkit for iOS provides an easy and convenient way of accessing Windows Azure storage from iOS-based applications.
The toolkit works in two ways – the toolkit can be used to access Windows Azure storage directly, or alternatively, can go through a proxy service known as the Cloud Ready package. The Cloud Ready code is the same code as used in the WP7 toolkit for Windows Azure (found here) and negates the need for the developer to store the Azure storage credentials locally on the device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Windows Azure Blob Storage and CDN with WordPress</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/08/using-windows-azure-blob-storage-and-cdn-with-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2011 20:59:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/08/using-windows-azure-blob-storage-and-cdn-with-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: In publishing this post, I encountered an issue with the plugin. Originally I used OneNote to create screen clippings of all the images in the post, then I pasted them into Live Writer. This is my normal practice for blog posts. Unfortunately, when I published, there ended up being a mismatch between the files stored in blob storage and those included in my blog post. However, when I updated the blog post and made actual JPEGs for each image (instead of screen clippings), everything worked fine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying the Windows Azure ASP.NET MVC 3 Web Role</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/08/deploying-the-windows-azure-asp.net-mvc-3-web-role/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2011 12:19:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/08/deploying-the-windows-azure-asp.net-mvc-3-web-role/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday Steve Marx and I covered the new Windows Azure Tools for Visual Studio 1.4 release on the Cloud Cover Show (will publish on Friday, 8/5). Since the tools shipped the same day as the show we literally only had an hour or so before the show to pull together a demonstration of some of the new capabilities. I think we did a reasonably good job, but I’d like to further clarify a few things in this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates to the Windows Azure Platform Training Kit</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/08/updates-to-the-windows-azure-platform-training-kit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2011 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/08/updates-to-the-windows-azure-platform-training-kit/</guid>
      <description>Today we released the Windows Azure Platform Training Kit – August 2011. The Windows Azure Platform Training Kit (WAPTK) includes a comprehensive set of technical content including hands-on labs, presentations, and demos that are designed to help you learn how to use the Windows Azure platform.
In addition to the offline training kit above, we have pushed updates to the Windows Azure Platform Training Course on MSDN.
What’s new in this release?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Azure Toolkit for iOS Now Supports the Access Control Service</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/07/windows-azure-toolkit-for-ios-now-supports-the-access-control-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2011 17:29:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/07/windows-azure-toolkit-for-ios-now-supports-the-access-control-service/</guid>
      <description>Today we released an update to our Windows Azure Toolkit for iOS that provides some significant enhancements – in particular, we now provide support for using the Windows Azure Access Control Server (ACS) from an iOS application. You can get all the bits here:
  (updated) watoolkitios-lib
  (updated) watoolkitios-samples
  (updated) watoolkitios-doc
  (new) watoolkitios-configutility
  (new) cloudreadypackages
  We first released this toolkit on May 6th, and since then we’ve released two minor updates and even accepted a merge request from the community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RELEASED: Windows Azure Toolkit for iOS V1.0.1</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/05/released-windows-azure-toolkit-for-ios-v1.0.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 16:40:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/05/released-windows-azure-toolkit-for-ios-v1.0.1/</guid>
      <description>Last night we released an update to the Windows Azure Toolkit for iOS. This release is a minor update that includes the refactoring of code for better conformance to standards, some bug updates, and a few additions to the sample application. You can take a look at the updates in each of the three repositories:
  https://github.com/microsoft-dpe/watoolkitios-lib
  https://github.com/microsoft-dpe/watoolkitios-samples
  https://github.com/microsoft-dpe/watoolkitios-doc
  One of the important updates is guidance—via the sample application—on how to use Windows Azure Queues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WPDT 7.1 Beta Support Added to the Windows Azure Toolkit for Windows Phone 7</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/05/wpdt-7.1-beta-support-added-to-the-windows-azure-toolkit-for-windows-phone-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 02:27:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/05/wpdt-7.1-beta-support-added-to-the-windows-azure-toolkit-for-windows-phone-7/</guid>
      <description>At this point I’m sure you’ve heard that the Windows Phone Developer Tools for &amp;ldquo;Mango&amp;rdquo; released today (also called the Windows Phone Developer Tools 7.1 Beta). To learn about these tools I suggest you review the following:
  Download &amp;amp; release notes: Windows Phone Developer Tools for Mango
  What’s New in Windows Phone Developer Tools
  Code Samples for Windows Phone
  To support the WPDT 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Your Services from the Windows Azure Toolkit for Windows Phone 7</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/05/deploying-your-services-from-the-windows-azure-toolkit-for-windows-phone-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 02:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/05/deploying-your-services-from-the-windows-azure-toolkit-for-windows-phone-7/</guid>
      <description>One of the most common requests I’ve received for the Windows Azure Toolkit for Windows Phone 7 has been a tutorial for deploying the services to Windows Azure. It’s taken longer than it should have—my humblest apologies—but I’ve finally put one together. You’ll need to follow the following steps outlined below:
  Create a Certificate (used for SSL)
  Export the PFX File
  Upload the PFX File to Windows Azure</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merged a Pull Request for the iOS Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/05/merged-a-pull-request-for-the-ios-toolkit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 20:02:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/05/merged-a-pull-request-for-the-ios-toolkit/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago, Fredrik Olsson opened a pull request against our GitHub repository for the Windows Azure Toolkit for iOS. A pull request provides a way to tell others about changes you’ve made to a repository – by sending me a pull request, Fredrik was notifying me of his updates so that I could review and, if appropriate, merge them to the main repository.
Today I merged Fredrik’s pull request.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VB.NET and Bug Fixes for Windows Azure Toolkit for Windows Phone 7 (v1.2.1)</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/05/vb.net-and-bug-fixes-for-windows-azure-toolkit-for-windows-phone-7-v1.2.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2011 16:22:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/05/vb.net-and-bug-fixes-for-windows-azure-toolkit-for-windows-phone-7-v1.2.1/</guid>
      <description>Today’s release of the Windows Azure Toolkit for Windows Phone 7 (v1.2.1) has two important updates:
  Support for Visual Basic
  Bug fixes
  You can download the latest drop here: http://watoolkitwp7.codeplex.com/releases/view/61952
Visual Basic
When we released on Monday we did not include updated project templates for Visual Basic – turns out that creating these project templates takes a long time, and we did not have enough cycles to complete it in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NOW AVAILABLE: Windows Azure Toolkit for Windows Phone 7 v1.2</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/05/now-available-windows-azure-toolkit-for-windows-phone-7-v1.2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 05:48:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/05/now-available-windows-azure-toolkit-for-windows-phone-7-v1.2/</guid>
      <description>Here it is – the Windows Azure Toolkit for Windows Phone 7 v1.2!
As I mentioned last week when I spoke about Updates Coming Soon to the Windows Azure Toolkit for Windows Phone 7, we have some really important and valuable additions to the toolkit.
  Support and tooling for the Access Control Service 2.0
  Support for Windows Azure Storage Queues
  Updated UI/UX for the management web application</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates Coming Soon to the Windows Azure Toolkit for Windows Phone 7</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/05/updates-coming-soon-to-the-windows-azure-toolkit-for-windows-phone-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 15:56:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/05/updates-coming-soon-to-the-windows-azure-toolkit-for-windows-phone-7/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been really pleased with our delivery cadence for the Windows Azure Toolkit for Windows Phone 7. We first launched (v1.0) on March 23, 2011 – this launch included VS project templates, class libraries for storage and membership services, a sample application, and documentation. We had excellent coverage by Mary Jo Foley, InfoQ, and others. On April 12, 2011—during MIX11—we shipped an update (v1.1) that provided support for Microsoft Push Notification Services running in Windows Azure (we also shipped some bug fixes).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Windows Azure for Windows Phone 7 Push Notification Support</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/05/using-windows-azure-for-windows-phone-7-push-notification-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 04:44:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/05/using-windows-azure-for-windows-phone-7-push-notification-support/</guid>
      <description>At MIX11 we released the Windows Azure Toolkit for Windows Phone 7 v1.1.0, which included out-of-the-box support for the Microsoft Push Notification Service (MPNS) for Windows Phone. The MPNS provides an efficient way for an application to register itself for updates that are pushed directly to the phone rather than writing the application to frequently poll a web service to look for pending notifications. This has the benefit of reducing the impact on your phone battery, as polling results in the device radio turning on frequently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with the Windows Azure Toolkit for iOS</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/05/getting-started-with-the-windows-azure-toolkit-for-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 22:48:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/05/getting-started-with-the-windows-azure-toolkit-for-ios/</guid>
      <description>IMPORTANT UPDATE:
 Since the initial launch of the Windows Azure Toolkit for iOS, we’ve not only updated &amp;amp; changed the library, but we’ve also renamed the repository. For the latest information, please visit our github repository at http://github.com/microsoft-dpe/ – from here you can get access to the iOS library, Android library, and all the additional tools we’ve made available.
 I am extremely excited to announce the immediate availability of the Windows Azure Toolkit for iOS!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Article: Introducing the Windows Azure AppFabric Caching Service</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/04/article-introducing-the-windows-azure-appfabric-caching-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 04:56:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/04/article-introducing-the-windows-azure-appfabric-caching-service/</guid>
      <description>I was excited to receive my MSDN Magazine in the mail this week, as an article written by myself and Karandeep Anand—a Principal Group Program Manager on the AppFabric team—was finally published. These things generally take a month or so from the time you finish writing them, which is often challenging in a services world.
You can now read this article online: Introducing the Windows Azure AppFabric Caching Service
link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with the Windows Azure Toolkit for Windows Phone 7</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/03/getting-started-with-the-windows-azure-toolkit-for-windows-phone-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 00:21:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/03/getting-started-with-the-windows-azure-toolkit-for-windows-phone-7/</guid>
      <description>I have just published a short screencast that demonstrates how to get started with the Windows Azure Toolkit for Windows Phone 7. This toolkit is designed to make it easy to build phone applications that use cloud services running in Windows Azure.
In this screencast you will learn:
  Where to download the toolkit
  How to install and setup the toolkit
  How to use the new project templates</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Azure Toolkit for Windows Phone 7</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/03/windows-azure-toolkit-for-windows-phone-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2011 07:16:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/03/windows-azure-toolkit-for-windows-phone-7/</guid>
      <description>I am tremendously excited to announce the release of the Windows Azure Toolkit for Windows Phone 7. This toolkit is designed to make it easier for your to build phone application that leverage cloud services running in Windows Azure. Our team has been diligently working on this toolkit for months, and I think you’ll like what you see.
Get the bits on CodePlex here: http://watoolkitwp7.codeplex.com/
Cloud services and phone applications are a powerful combination, and our goal is to make it as easy as we can for you to use Windows Azure to provide storage and services for your phone applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Requesting Access to the VM Role Beta</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/03/requesting-access-to-the-vm-role-beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 04:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/03/requesting-access-to-the-vm-role-beta/</guid>
      <description>I often hear from people that they want to try out the Virtual Machine Role (VM Role for short) but cannot find it in the Windows Azure portal and don’t see the option in Visual Studio. This is because it is still in beta and requires you to request access—and receive acceptance—into the program. Fortunately, we make it very easy to get accepted – essentially request access, wait a week, and you’re in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Azure Platform Training Kit and Course, February 2011 Update</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/03/windows-azure-platform-training-kit-and-course-february-2011-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2011 20:36:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/03/windows-azure-platform-training-kit-and-course-february-2011-update/</guid>
      <description>link
The February 2011 update of the Windows Azure Platform Training Kit includes several updates and bug fixes for the hands-on labs. Most of the updates were focused on supporting the new Windows Azure AppFabric February CTP and the new portal experience for AppFabric Caching, Access Control, and the Service Bus. The specific content that was updated in this release includes:
  Hands-on Lab - Building Windows Azure Apps with the Caching service</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Multiple Websites in a Windows Azure Web Role</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/02/running-multiple-websites-in-a-windows-azure-web-role/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 06:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/02/running-multiple-websites-in-a-windows-azure-web-role/</guid>
      <description>Prior to the release of the Windows Azure 1.3 SDK, Web roles hosted your application in IIS Hosted Web Core (HWC). While there were certainly ways to extend HWC, for the most part you were stuck with a single application bound to no more than a single HTTP or HTTPS endpoint. This model enabled only a minimal number of configurations, and prevented you from fully benefiting from the full capabilities of IIS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing the SecureString in the DataCacheSecurity Constructor</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/02/managing-the-securestring-in-the-datacachesecurity-constructor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2011 18:42:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/02/managing-the-securestring-in-the-datacachesecurity-constructor/</guid>
      <description>If you take a good look at the latest Release Notes for the Windows Azure AppFabric CTP February Release – or if you jump directly into the new SDK and try to programmatically configure the Caching client – you’ll quickly discover that the DataCacheSecurity class now requires a System.Security.SecureString instead of a string.
The reason for this change in the DataCacheSecurity constructor is to reduce the time that an unencrypted string remains in memory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Azure AppFabric CTP February, Caching Enhancements, and the New LABS Portal</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/02/windows-azure-appfabric-ctp-february-caching-enhancements-and-the-new-labs-portal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2011 03:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/02/windows-azure-appfabric-ctp-february-caching-enhancements-and-the-new-labs-portal/</guid>
      <description>I’m excited to tell you about the Windows Azure AppFabric CTP February release. There are a number of enhancements and improvements coming with this release, including:
  New Silverlight-based LABS portal, bringing consistency with the production Windows Azure portal.
  Ability to select either a 128MB or 256MB cache size.
  Ability to dynamically upgrade or downgrade your cache size.
  Improved diagnostics with client side tracing and client request tracking capabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Families and the Oil of Monkeys</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/02/families-and-the-oil-of-monkeys/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2011 04:53:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/02/families-and-the-oil-of-monkeys/</guid>
      <description>Pardon the indulgence, but this post is not related to Windows Azure, cloud computing, or technology whatsoever. Instead, it’s a celebration of my wonderful family, and the fun we have.
It all started one morning with a simple email from my sister. It degraded into a war of “poetry” that, to this day, is still unresolved. It’s become one of those things that we never talk about in person, but is resurrected over email by my mother.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Azure Platform Training Kit and Course, January 2011 Update</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/01/windows-azure-platform-training-kit-and-course-january-2011-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 19:17:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/01/windows-azure-platform-training-kit-and-course-january-2011-update/</guid>
      <description>I am thrilled to announce that we have released a January 2011 update to the Windows Azure Platform Training Kit &amp;amp; Training Course.
The Windows Azure Platform Training Kit &amp;amp; Training Course includes a comprehensive set of technical content including hands-on labs, presentations, and demos that are designed to help you learn how to use the Windows Azure platform, including: Windows Azure, SQL Azure and the Windows Azure AppFabric.
Download the Windows Azure Platform Training Kit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Expression Encoder 4 in a Windows Azure Worker Role</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/01/using-expression-encoder-4-in-a-windows-azure-worker-role/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2011 06:26:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/01/using-expression-encoder-4-in-a-windows-azure-worker-role/</guid>
      <description>One of the most common workloads I hear about from customers and developers is video encoding in Windows Azure. There are certainly many ways to perform video encoding in Windows Azure – in fact, at PDC 2009 I was joined by Mark Richards of Origin Digital who discussed their video transcoding solution on Windows Azure – but until the release of Windows Azure 1.3 SDK, and in particular Startup Tasks and elevated privileges, it was complicated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overlay Text On Video Using Expression Encoder 4</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/01/overlay-text-on-video-using-expression-encoder-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 01:10:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/01/overlay-text-on-video-using-expression-encoder-4/</guid>
      <description>I recently built an application where I wanted to write some arbitrary text onto a video. I was using Expression Encoder 4 and had a difficult time finding some examples and documentation, aside from some basic MSDN documentation on the MediaItem class. I was eventually able to figure it out, but it took a little time. Even though the end result is not particularly glamorous, I thought I’d save you some time and share what I learned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programmatically Changing the AppPool Identity in a Windows Azure Web Role</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/01/programmatically-changing-the-apppool-identity-in-a-windows-azure-web-role/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2011 18:49:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/01/programmatically-changing-the-apppool-identity-in-a-windows-azure-web-role/</guid>
      <description>With the Windows Azure SDK 1.3 comes full support for IIS in web roles, giving your web roles the ability to access the full range of web service features available in IIS. This provides a lot of powerful capabilities, some of which are outlined here.
By default, the AppPool runs as the NetworkService. Go ahead and create a new Windows Azure Project, choose a web role, and hit F5 to run it in IIS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Come Join My Team!</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/01/come-join-my-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2011 17:14:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2011/01/come-join-my-team/</guid>
      <description>One of the best career decisions I’ve made was to join the Windows Azure Platform Evangelism team last July. Yes, it was a lot of work to uproot the family and move to Seattle, but it was absolutely worth it. I pinch myself nearly everyday to make sure that it’s not just a dream – the opportunities here are tremendous:
  Work with an incredible group of smart, driven, technical leaders</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Deploy with Windows Azure on Restrictive Networks</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/12/web-deploy-with-windows-azure-on-restrictive-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2010 18:10:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/12/web-deploy-with-windows-azure-on-restrictive-networks/</guid>
      <description>Some networks are more restrictive than others, and (much to my continual chagrin) this is especially true here at Microsoft. As I wrote and tested the post Using Web Deploy with Windows Azure for Rapid Development, I found that I was not able to use Web Deploy on port 8172; turns out that we prevent SSL traffic on any port but 443. Fortunately, it’s pretty easy to resolve this restriction by modifying the Input Endpoint values in the Service Definition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Web Deploy with Windows Azure for Rapid Development</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/12/using-web-deploy-with-windows-azure-for-rapid-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2010 19:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/12/using-web-deploy-with-windows-azure-for-rapid-development/</guid>
      <description>Update: Ryan Dunn has just posted Using Web Deploy with Windows Azure that shows a way to use plugins to simplify the process of using Web Deploy with Windows Azure. He also provides a lot of nice commentary and context around the solution. Definitely worth reading.
While building your web application, have you ever deployed to Windows Azure and then realized you forgot to make a change? Or forgot to include an update?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye lunch for Ryan Dunn</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/12/goodbye-lunch-for-ryan-dunn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2010 06:51:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/12/goodbye-lunch-for-ryan-dunn/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this week we had a team lunch to wish Ryan Dunn well as he moves on to new challenges outside of Microsoft.
You’ll be missed, Ryan.
For the greatest “sappy montage” of all time, watch this clip from Cloud Cover Episode 33.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Try out the WordPress app for Windows Phone 7</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/12/try-out-the-wordpress-app-for-windows-phone-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2010 06:47:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/12/try-out-the-wordpress-app-for-windows-phone-7/</guid>
      <description>link
This application looks pretty awesome. In addition to giving me the ability to post to my blog directly from my Windows Phone, it looks like I can also: create &amp;amp; edit pages, moderate comments, and review my blog statistics (not that it’s impressive).
I’ve been very happy with the applications hitting the Windows Phone Marketplace – just last week I discovered an application to help me manage my Windows Home Server from the phone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use the WAPTK to help setup your Windows Azure development environment</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/12/use-the-waptk-to-help-setup-your-windows-azure-development-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2010 18:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/12/use-the-waptk-to-help-setup-your-windows-azure-development-environment/</guid>
      <description>As awesome as it is to have a lot of great local development tools, it’s also be difficult to setup new development environments. Downloading and installing the Windows Azure SDK is really only one step – you also have to ensure that local services are configured correctly (e.g. IIS), you may need additional SDKs (e.g. Windows Identity Foundation SDK), setup additional tools (e.g. SSMS), and so on. Not only does this take time but also organizational skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Azure Platform Training Kit, December 2010 Update</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/12/windows-azure-platform-training-kit-december-2010-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2010 19:58:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/12/windows-azure-platform-training-kit-december-2010-update/</guid>
      <description>I am happy to announce that we have released the December 2010 update to the Windows Azure Platform Training Kit.
The Windows Azure Platform Training Kit includes a comprehensive set of technical content including hands-on labs, presentations, and demos that are designed to help you learn how to use the Windows Azure platform including: Windows Azure, SQL Azure and the Windows Azure AppFabric.
The December update provides new and updated hands-on labs, demo scripts, and presentations for the Windows Azure November 2010 enhancements and the Windows Azure Tools for Microsoft Visual Studio 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Article: Re-Introducing the Windows Azure AppFabric Access Control Service</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/12/article-re-introducing-the-windows-azure-appfabric-access-control-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2010 00:04:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/12/article-re-introducing-the-windows-azure-appfabric-access-control-service/</guid>
      <description>I had the great pleasure of co-authoring an article with my teammate Vittorio Bertocci on the September LABS release of the Windows Azure AppFabric Access Control. This article, entitled Re-Introducing the Windows Azure AppFabric Access Control Service, walks you through the process of authenticating and authorizing users on your Web site by leveraging existing identity providers such as Windows Live ID, Facebook, Yahoo!, and Google. Specifically, this article covers:
  Outsourcing Authentication of a Web Site to the Access Control Service (ACS)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programmatically Configuring the Caching Client</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/12/programmatically-configuring-the-caching-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 13:38:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/12/programmatically-configuring-the-caching-client/</guid>
      <description>When using Windows Azure AppFabric Caching you will have to configure the caching client to use a provisioned cache. In the past I’ve given examples of doing this using an application configuration file, but there are times where you may want to programmatically configure the caching client. Fortunately, it’s really quite easy and straight forward.
Caching Client Code
  // define the cache details
  string serviceUrl = &amp;ldquo;YOURNAMESPACE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up the BidNow Sample Application for Windows Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/12/setting-up-the-bidnow-sample-application-for-windows-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 00:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/12/setting-up-the-bidnow-sample-application-for-windows-azure/</guid>
      <description>Update: Recent updates to the Windows Azure AppFabric CTP (see here) have made some of the steps shown in this video incorrect. Please review Getting Started with BidNow and Deploy BidNow to the Cloud for updates.

This video provides a walkthrough of the steps required to get the BidNow Sample up and running on your computer.
BidNow is an online auction site that shows how our comprehensive set of cloud services can be used to develop a highly scalable consumer application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Significant Updates Released in the BidNow Sample for Windows Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/11/significant-updates-released-in-the-bidnow-sample-for-windows-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 17:16:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/11/significant-updates-released-in-the-bidnow-sample-for-windows-azure/</guid>
      <description>Click here if you want to quickly grab the latest version of the BidNow sample. Click here if you want to see a live demo of the application.
There have been a host of announcements and releases over the last month for the Windows Azure Platform. It started at the Professional Developers Conference (PDC) in Redmond, where we announced new services such as Windows Azure AppFabric Caching and SQL Azure Reporting, as well as new features for Windows Azure, such as VM Role, Admin mode, RDP, Full IIS, and a new portal experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the SAML CredentialType to Authenticate to the Service Bus</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/11/using-the-saml-credentialtype-to-authenticate-to-the-service-bus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2010 05:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/11/using-the-saml-credentialtype-to-authenticate-to-the-service-bus/</guid>
      <description>The Windows Azure AppFabric Service Bus uses a class called TransportClientEndpointBehavior to specify the credentials for a particular endpoint. There are four options available to you: Unauthenticated, SimpleWebToken, SharedSecret, and SAML. For details, take a look at the CredentialType member. The first three are pretty well described and documented – in fact, if you’ve spent any time at all looking at the Service Bus, you’ve probably seen the following code:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hands-On Lab: Building Windows Azure Applications with the Caching Service</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/11/hands-on-lab-building-windows-azure-applications-with-the-caching-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 22:51:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/11/hands-on-lab-building-windows-azure-applications-with-the-caching-service/</guid>
      <description>Recently my team quietly released an update to the Windows Azure Platform Training Course (the training course is similar to the training kit, with minor differences) to coincide with new services released at PDC10. There’s a lot of nice updates in this release, including a new hands-on lab called Building Windows Azure Applications with the Caching Service, focused on building Windows Azure applications with the new Windows Azure AppFabric Caching service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code for the Windows Azure AppFabric Caching demo</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/11/code-for-the-windows-azure-appfabric-caching-demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 18:03:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/11/code-for-the-windows-azure-appfabric-caching-demo/</guid>
      <description>This post is long overdo. At PDC10 I recorded the session Introduction to Windows Azure AppFabric Caching, where I introduced the new Caching service. As part of the presentation I gave a demo where I updated an existing ASP.NET web application running in a Windows Azure web role to use the caching service. For details on the caching service, please watch the presentation.
In this presentation I showed three uses of the caching service:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TechEd EMEA: A Lap Around the Windows Azure AppFabric (ASI205)</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/11/teched-emea-a-lap-around-the-windows-azure-appfabric-asi205/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2010 15:12:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/11/teched-emea-a-lap-around-the-windows-azure-appfabric-asi205/</guid>
      <description>Not only is this my first time at TechEd EMEA, but it’s also my first time to Berlin. While exhausting, it’s been a ton of fun! I haven’t had a much time to explore the city yet, but I’ve spent a lot of time talking to customers about the Windows Azure Platform.
Today I am delivering the presentation A Lap Around the Windows Azure AppFabric.
A Lap Around the Windows Azure AppFabric</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PDC10: Introduction to Windows Azure AppFabric Caching (CS60)</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/11/pdc10-introduction-to-windows-azure-appfabric-caching-cs60/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2010 16:29:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/11/pdc10-introduction-to-windows-azure-appfabric-caching-cs60/</guid>
      <description>In addition to building the Composite Application keynote demo presented by James Conard and Bob Muglia, I presented a session on the new Windows Azure AppFabric Caching service that’s now available as a CTP release in the AppFabric LABS environment. You can find the presentation here: http://player.microsoftpdc.com/Session/1f607983-c6eb-4d9f-b644-55247e8adda6
link
A few interesting notes on the Caching service:
  It’s a distributed, in-memory, application cache provided entirely as a service – no installation, management, or deployment required</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Services and Enhancements with the Windows Azure AppFabric</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/10/new-services-and-enhancements-with-the-windows-azure-appfabric/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2010 17:46:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/10/new-services-and-enhancements-with-the-windows-azure-appfabric/</guid>
      <description>Today’s an exciting day! During the keynote this morning at PDC10, Bob Muglia announced a wave of new building block services and capabilities for the Windows Azure AppFabric. The purpose of the Windows Azure AppFabric is to provide a comprehensive cloud platform for developing, deploying and managing applications, extending the way you build Windows Azure applications today. At PDC09, we announced both Windows Azure AppFabric and Windows Server AppFabric, highlighting a commitment to deliver a set of complimentary services both in the cloud and on-premises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What have I been doing for PDC10?</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/10/what-have-i-been-doing-for-pdc10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 19:57:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/10/what-have-i-been-doing-for-pdc10/</guid>
      <description>While I’ve been involved with the Professional Developers Conference (PDC) in the past (keynote in ‘08, breakout in ‘08, and breakout in ‘09), I’ve never been as personally vested and involved as I am this year. Whether you look at as a perk or curse, it’s one of the jobs I signed up for when I took the roll as a Technical Evangelist for the Windows Azure Platform (personally, I love it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Reasons I’m Excited About IE9</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/09/7-reasons-im-excited-about-ie9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2010 22:51:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/09/7-reasons-im-excited-about-ie9/</guid>
      <description>The IE9 beta was released today, and I’m really excited. Sure, it supports HTML5 and modern web standards, leverages hardware acceleration to make it faster than any other browser on the world, and more. But that’s not what really gets me excited about it.
 ![]() ![](Preview.png) ![Get Microsoft Silverlight](http://go2.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=108181) [ ![Get Microsoft Silverlight]() ](http://go2.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=124807)  DoKashiteru / CC BY 2.5
For those of you unable to watch the above video, let me spell it out:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Bus on the Cloud Cover Show</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/08/service-bus-on-the-cloud-cover-show/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2010 19:01:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/08/service-bus-on-the-cloud-cover-show/</guid>
      <description>Ryan Dunn and Steve Marx have a great show on Channel9 called the Cloud Cover Show. I’ve been watching it since the beginning, and have learned a lot about different features of the Windows Azure Platform, the latest news and announcements, as well as tips and tricks. Naturally, I was honored (and a bit scared) when they asked me to join them on the show to talk about the Windows Azure AppFabric Service Bus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the ‘TrustServerCertificate’ Property with SQL Azure and Entity Framework</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/08/using-the-trustservercertificate-property-with-sql-azure-and-entity-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2010 04:48:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/08/using-the-trustservercertificate-property-with-sql-azure-and-entity-framework/</guid>
      <description>I’ve spent the last few days refactoring a web application to leverage SQL Server via Entity Framework 4.0 (EF4) in preparation for migrating it to SQL Azure. It’s a neat application, and a great example of how to fully encapsulate your data tier (the previous version had issues due to tight coupling between the data and web tier). More on this soon.
So, when I deployed my database to SQL Azure (using the SQL Azure Migration Wizard) I was confounded by the following error:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Azure Adds Support for Database Copy</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/08/sql-azure-adds-support-for-database-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2010 04:36:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/08/sql-azure-adds-support-for-database-copy/</guid>
      <description>The SQL Azure team has announced SQL Azure Service Update 4, which includes database copy, an improved help system, and deployment of Microsoft Project Code-Named “Houston” to multiple data centers. See the SQL Azure Team Blog for the formal announcement.
Customers have been asking for a way to backup databases with SQL Azure for a long time, and the new database copy capabilities will provide a lot of support. From the SQL Azure Team Blog:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AutoStart WCF Services to Expose them as Service Bus Endpoints</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/08/autostart-wcf-services-to-expose-them-as-service-bus-endpoints/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2010 16:30:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/08/autostart-wcf-services-to-expose-them-as-service-bus-endpoints/</guid>
      <description>A couple months ago I wrote a post on how to host WCF services in IIS that expose themselves as endpoints on the Windows Azure AppFabric Service Bus. The principal challenge in this scenario is that IIS/WAS relies on message-based activation and will only launch the host after the first request comes in. However, until the host is launched the service will not connect to the Service Bus, and consequently will never receive a message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring an ASP.NET Web Application to Use a Windows Server AppFabric Cache for Session State</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/08/configuring-an-asp.net-web-application-to-use-a-windows-server-appfabric-cache-for-session-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2010 22:36:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/08/configuring-an-asp.net-web-application-to-use-a-windows-server-appfabric-cache-for-session-state/</guid>
      <description>Last week I spent some time setting up Windows Server AppFabric Cache in anticipation of additional tasks this week. The first task is configuring an ASP.NET web application to use Windows Server AppFabric Caching for the Session State Provider. This allows the web application to spread session objects across the entire cache cluster, resulting in greater scalability.
Below is a walkthrough on how to configure this scenario. In addition to this post, I recommend you take a look at this article on MSDN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Windows Server AppFabric Cache</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/08/getting-started-with-windows-server-appfabric-cache/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2010 21:22:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/08/getting-started-with-windows-server-appfabric-cache/</guid>
      <description>I struggled today to find a good “Getting started with Windows Server AppFabric Cache” tutorial – either my _search fu _failed me or it simply doesn’t exist. Nevertheless, I was able to piece together the information I needed to get started.
I recommend you break this up into three steps:
  Installing Windows Server AppFabric
  Configuring Windows Server AppFabric Cache
  Testing Windows Server AppFabric Cache with Sample Apps</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated Windows Azure AppFabric SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/08/updated-windows-azure-appfabric-sdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2010 22:36:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/08/updated-windows-azure-appfabric-sdk/</guid>
      <description>Today the Windows Azure AppFabric team released an update to the SDK. This release is what’s called a QFE (quick fix engineering) update that’s intended to address bugs or breaking issues. To my knowledge, this is the first QFE for the Windows Azure AppFabric. In this case, the QFE fixed one bug:
 Adding a Ws2007HttpRelayBinding endpoint that uses TransportWithMessageCredential security mode to a ServiceHost that also exposes a local MEX endpoint (not visible through the Service Bus) using the mexHttpsBinding, causes the local MEX endpoint to stop working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the Expression Encoder SDK to encode lots of videos</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/08/using-the-expression-encoder-sdk-to-encode-lots-of-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2010 05:31:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/08/using-the-expression-encoder-sdk-to-encode-lots-of-videos/</guid>
      <description>I spent a good deal of time this weekend importing hours and hours family videos off our Mini DV cassettes. Lots of fun, and LOTS of video! Based on the size of these files, I was quite close to running out of room on my Windows Media Center. So, I decided to encode the files as WMVs. Huge size reduction with very little quality loss.
I decided to use Microsoft Expression Encoder 3 – a great tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Article: Tips for Migrating Your Applications to the Cloud</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/08/article-tips-for-migrating-your-applications-to-the-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2010 15:36:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/08/article-tips-for-migrating-your-applications-to-the-cloud/</guid>
      <description>I had the great pleasure of co-authoring an article on application migration to Windows Azure for MSDN Magazine with my friend George Huey, creator of the SQL Azure Migration Wizard. This article stems from our work helping dozens of customers – both small and big – migrate their existing applications to run in the cloud.
link
(Ours is the second down on the left.)
While this article is by no means exhaustive, we did try to explain some of the common patterns and scenarios we faced when helping customers migrate their applications into Windows Azure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use social web providers in less than 5 minutes</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/08/use-social-web-providers-in-less-than-5-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2010 05:13:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/08/use-social-web-providers-in-less-than-5-minutes/</guid>
      <description>Significant Access Control Service (ACS) updates released to AppFabric LABS environment today. Take a look at the Windows Azure AppFabric team blog for the formal announcement. I’d rather show you a quick demo.
 ![]() ![](Preview.png) ![Get Microsoft Silverlight](http://go2.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=108181) [ ![Get Microsoft Silverlight]() ](http://go2.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=124807)  Quick summary of new capabilities in the Access Control Service:
  Integration with Windows Identity Foundation (WIF) and tooling
  Out-of-the-box support for popular web identity providers including: Windows Live ID, OpenID, Google, Yahoo, and Facebook</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the default SQL Server instance for Windows Azure development storage</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/07/using-the-default-sql-server-instance-for-windows-azure-development-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2010 18:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/07/using-the-default-sql-server-instance-for-windows-azure-development-storage/</guid>
      <description>This tip isn’t new, but it’s still useful. I found myself building a new development box this week, and I didn’t want to use SQLExpress for the Windows Azure development storage. Instead, I wanted to use the default instance for SQL Server.
It’s pretty simple to do this – after you install the Windows Azure SDK and Tools, go to a command prompt and browse to the following folder: C:Program FilesWindows Azure SDKv1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How would you describe the Windows Azure AppFabric?</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/07/how-would-you-describe-the-windows-azure-appfabric/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2010 03:57:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/07/how-would-you-describe-the-windows-azure-appfabric/</guid>
      <description>I was reading through the FAQ document for the Windows Azure platform this evening (what else is there to do on a Sunday night?), and I came across the following:
 What is the Windows Azure AppFabric?
With AppFabric, Microsoft is delivering services that enable developers to build and manage composite applications more easily for both server and cloud environments. Windows Azure AppFabric, formerly called “.NET Services”, provides cloud-based services that help developers connect applications and services across Windows Azure, Windows Server and a number of other platforms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Week as a Technical Evangelist</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/07/my-first-week-as-a-technical-evangelist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2010 01:11:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/07/my-first-week-as-a-technical-evangelist/</guid>
      <description>I definitely luck out when it comes to the first day on the job. My first day as an Architect Evangelist was at a team offsite in Las Vegas. This time around, as a Technical Evangelist, my team hosted a Windows Azure platform Software Design Review (SDR) for customers up in Redmond. A SDR is an opportunity for customers to join product teams and review current and future states of the technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-World Patterns for Cloud Computing at TechEd NA 2010</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/06/real-world-patterns-for-cloud-computing-at-teched-na-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2010 04:14:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/06/real-world-patterns-for-cloud-computing-at-teched-na-2010/</guid>
      <description>It was an amazing TechEd NA 2010, and I admit that it took me a few days to recover. Between the heat and humidity, great times with friends, and good food, I managed to spend a bit of time at the conference.
I had the pleasure of co-presenting with Jerome Schulist, a solutions architect at the Tribune Company. Jerome is one of the architects that engineered the solution that has allowed the Tribune Company to store and process terabytes of data on the Windows Azure platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Host WCF Services in IIS with Service Bus Endpoints</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/05/host-wcf-services-in-iis-with-service-bus-endpoints/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2010 03:56:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/05/host-wcf-services-in-iis-with-service-bus-endpoints/</guid>
      <description>Update: To see how to leverage Windows Azure AppFabric Autostart to activate the WCF Service, please see AutoStart WCF Services to Expose them as Service Bus Endpoints.
Vishal Chowdhary, a Senior Test Lead on the Azure AppFabric team, recently posted a whitepaper on hosting WCF services with Service Bus endpoints from IIS. This whitepaper provides two solutions to a (previously) significant challenge in hosting WCF services in IIS that connect to the Azure AppFabric Service Bus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the .NET Framework 4.0 with the Azure AppFabric SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/05/using-the-.net-framework-4.0-with-the-azure-appfabric-sdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2010 21:01:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/05/using-the-.net-framework-4.0-with-the-azure-appfabric-sdk/</guid>
      <description>The other day I attempted to build a sample application that communicated with the Azure AppFabric Service Bus by creating a Console application targeting the .NET Framework 4.0. After adding a reference to Microsoft.ServiceBus I was bewildered to see that my Service Bus bindings in the system.ServiceModel section were not recognized.
I soon realized that the issue was the machine.config file. When you install the Azure AppFabric SDK the relevant WCF extensions are added to the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release the hounds - Multicasting with Azure AppFabric</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/05/release-the-hounds-multicasting-with-azure-appfabric/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2010 05:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/05/release-the-hounds-multicasting-with-azure-appfabric/</guid>
      <description>On an email thread today, someone was looking for suggestions on how to start a job simultaneously across multiple worker roles running in Windows Azure. For example, image you have ten worker roles already running and, through the command of an admin or user, you want to “release the hounds!”
Definitely an interesting scenario, and many different ways to approach it. Initial ideas and thoughts centered around using Windows Azure storage tables or blobs – in fact, Steve Marx quickly threw out some pseudo code highlighting a reasonable way to approach the problem:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jon Box on the Capabilities of Internet Explorer 8</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/05/jon-box-on-the-capabilities-of-internet-explorer-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2010 21:43:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/05/jon-box-on-the-capabilities-of-internet-explorer-8/</guid>
      <description>At MIX10, Jon Box – a Senior Architect Evangelist with Microsoft – spoke with SocialWendy about Internet Explorer 8. In addition to highlighting the fact that IE8 makes the Internet easier, safer, and faster, Jon talks about three unique capabilities found in IE8:
  Accelerators
  Visual Search
  Web slices
  Furthermore, Jon highlighted how a web slice allows a user to subscribe to a piece of content on a web page, and also explain how a user can leverage an accelerator – such as Walmart’s accelerator – to make it easier to search for information and goods on the Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the Azure AppFabric?</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/05/what-is-the-azure-appfabric/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2010 16:19:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/05/what-is-the-azure-appfabric/</guid>
      <description>If you take a look at the official Windows Azure platform website, you’ll see two definitions for the Windows Azure platform AppFabric (hereafter referred to as the Azure AppFabric) prominently called out:
  “&amp;hellip; connects cloud services and on-premises applications.”
  “&amp;hellip; helps developers connect applications and services in the cloud or on-premises.”
  While the purpose of the Azure AppFabric seems clear to me – enable developers to connect applications and services – there are a couple things that generally cause confusion: execution and branding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Role: Technical Evangelist for Azure AppFabric</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/05/new-role-technical-evangelist-for-azure-appfabric/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2010 00:55:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/05/new-role-technical-evangelist-for-azure-appfabric/</guid>
      <description>I am excited to share that I’m taking the role of Technical Evangelist for the Windows Azure platform, focused on the Azure AppFabric. I’m joining James Conard’s team that focuses on Windows Azure platform evangelism, working with David Aiken, Ryan Dunn, Zach Owens, and Vittorio Bertocci – truly an all-star team! Oh, and I hope to spend a lot more time with Jack Greenfield, Clemens Vasters, Justin Smith, and everyone else on the AppFabric team!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silverlight Customers Light Up the Web</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/03/silverlight-customers-light-up-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2010 17:45:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/03/silverlight-customers-light-up-the-web/</guid>
      <description>Take a look at this great highlight reel featuring a number of great customer solutions that leverage Microsoft Silverlight. In particular, look for solutions from great customers like:
  CT Corporation, a Wolters Kluwer business
  McDonalds Corporation
  Winchester Ammunition
  National Instruments
  More to come on some of the great solutions and technologies highlighted at MIX 2010!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with XNA Development</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/01/getting-started-with-xna-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2010 16:50:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2010/01/getting-started-with-xna-development/</guid>
      <description>I love gaming. Long before the death match 95 tournament with Windows 95 that featured Bill Gates in a trench coat, I was playing computer games. Two of the first games I remember playing were The Ancient Art of War and Montezuma’s Revenge – simple but fun. I soon became a Sierra devotee, and devoured games such as Kings Quest, Heroes Quest (renamed Quest for Glory), Space Quest, Police Quest, and Leisure Suit Larry (just don’t tell my dad).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Significant updates to the SQL Azure Migration Wizard</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/12/significant-updates-to-the-sql-azure-migration-wizard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2009 18:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/12/significant-updates-to-the-sql-azure-migration-wizard/</guid>
      <description>George Huey has done it again! He has just published some significant updates to the SQL Azure Migration Wizard.
Previously, I’ve described the SQL Azure Migration Wizard as a tool that helps you migrate your SQL Server database into SQL Azure. This is still true, but now, thanks to updates made by George Huey, you can also migrate from SQL Azure-to-SQL Server and SQL Azure-to-SQL Azure. These are significant updates to the tool!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WI Azure User Group – Windows Azure Platform update</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/12/wi-azure-user-group-windows-azure-platform-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2009 16:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/12/wi-azure-user-group-windows-azure-platform-update/</guid>
      <description>Last week I presented at the Wisconsin Azure User Group for the second time, along with Clark Sell. Our goal was to provide an overview of everything announced at the Professional Developers Conference (PDC) 2009. We made a ton of announcements, and I recommend you check out the Microsoft PDC website for more information, including videos and decks from all the presentations.
 Shameless plug: watch my session on migrating applications to the Windows Azure platform with Accenture, CCH, Dominos, and Original Digital – Lessons Learned: Migrating Applications to the Windows Azure Platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preview of “Lessons Learned: Migrating Applications to the Windows Azure Platform”</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/11/preview-of-lessons-learned-migrating-applications-to-the-windows-azure-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2009 01:04:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/11/preview-of-lessons-learned-migrating-applications-to-the-windows-azure-platform/</guid>
      <description>It’s hard to believe that the Professional Developers Conference (PDC) 2009 is less than two weeks away. It doesn’t seem that long ago that I sat behind the stage at PDC 2008 providing support for the RedPrairie keynote with Bob Muglia and spoke in a breakout session with Jack Greenfield on Multi-Enterprise Business Applications. I’ll be back again this year, and I’m giving another talk – this time on lessons learned when migrating applications to the Windows Azure platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Leverage the RoleEntryPoint in an Azure Web Role</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/11/how-to-leverage-the-roleentrypoint-in-an-azure-web-role/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2009 14:24:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/11/how-to-leverage-the-roleentrypoint-in-an-azure-web-role/</guid>
      <description>One of the advantages to the approach our teams building the Windows Azure Platform have taken is flexibility. Recently, when I spoke at the Day of Cloud presentation, I recall Don Schwarz from Google making these two points (you can see video of his talk here):
  You can’t spin up your own threads in Google App Engine.
  You build your applications according to how Google thinks your apps should be built (the argument being that Google knows how to run highly available services at scale, which I think is a fair statement).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chunking BCP output to upload lots of data into SQL Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/11/chunking-bcp-output-to-upload-lots-of-data-into-sql-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2009 17:28:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/11/chunking-bcp-output-to-upload-lots-of-data-into-sql-azure/</guid>
      <description>Note: This is a guest post from George Huey, Architect Evangelist in the Developer and Platform Evangelism group.
When you upload your data into SQL Azure, SQL Azure replicates your data to three different locations in order to provide triple redundancy. Therefore, it needs a little more time to get the data in the proper places.
One of the things that we found out during a series of Windows Azure Platform Migration Labs held in the Chicago MTC is that you cannot upload hundreds of thousands of records without giving SQL Azure time to catch up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taste of Chicago benefits from Windows Azure and Silverlight</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/10/taste-of-chicago-benefits-from-windows-azure-and-silverlight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2009 16:34:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/10/taste-of-chicago-benefits-from-windows-azure-and-silverlight/</guid>
      <description>As a native Illinoisan, I know that the Taste of Chicago is a big deal! It is the largest outdoor food and music festival in the world, and is attended by more than 3 million people each year. If you like food and music, this is a festival for you!
This past year, the City of Chicago needed to quickly build out an interactive map for the event – and when I say quickly, I mean it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presenting on the Windows Azure Platform at the Day of Cloud</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/10/presenting-on-the-windows-azure-platform-at-the-day-of-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2009 14:14:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/10/presenting-on-the-windows-azure-platform-at-the-day-of-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Today I presented on the Windows Azure Platform at the Day of Cloud conference, in Chicago, IL. This conference was hosted by Tech in the Middle, and gave speakers the opportunity to present on SalesForce.com, the Windows Azure Platform (yours truly), Amazon Web Services, and Google App Engine. A great concept, and a lot of fun.
Gabe and Scott from Tech in the Middle recorded and posted each of these talks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The SQL Azure Migration Wizard will now migrate your data!</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/10/the-sql-azure-migration-wizard-will-now-migrate-your-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2009 17:50:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/10/the-sql-azure-migration-wizard-will-now-migrate-your-data/</guid>
      <description>Last month I blogged about the SQL Azure Migration Wizard created by George Huey. This tool helps you to migrate your SQL Server database into SQL Azure and is available up on Codeplex. To date, this tool has been downloaded almost a thousand times!
The number one request for the migration wizard was the ability to replicate your data up to SQL Azure (in addition to the SQL schema, which it already does).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Azure Database is Feature Complete!</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/10/sql-azure-database-is-feature-complete/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2009 14:53:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/10/sql-azure-database-is-feature-complete/</guid>
      <description>As many of you probably already know, the CTP of SQL Azure is now feature complete! Fantastic work by the SQL Azure product team, as it was only in August that they announced the opening of the SQL Azure Database CTP!
I recommend reading the entire announcement on the SQL Azure team&amp;rsquo;s blog. Here are some brief notes on the announcement:
  Details
  CTP 2 (announced yesterday, October 15th) represents the complete set of features that will be available at commercial launch this November at PDC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webcast: Running an ASP.NET MVC Web Application in Windows Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/10/webcast-running-an-asp.net-mvc-web-application-in-windows-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2009 16:59:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/10/webcast-running-an-asp.net-mvc-web-application-in-windows-azure/</guid>
      <description>I have seen enough people ask about running ASP.NET MVC Web Applications in Windows Azure that I thought I&amp;rsquo;d put together a short, quick webcast that shows exactly the steps you need to take. With the further ado &amp;hellip;
 ![](ASP.NET MVC in Windows Azure_Thumb.jpg) ![](Preview.png) ![Get Microsoft Silverlight](http://go2.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=108181) [ ![Get Microsoft Silverlight]() ](http://go2.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=124807)  Before you try this yourself, make sure you satisfy the following dependencies:
  Visual Studio 2008 with SP1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passive Federation with Windows Azure and ADFS v2</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/10/passive-federation-with-windows-azure-and-adfs-v2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2009 15:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/10/passive-federation-with-windows-azure-and-adfs-v2/</guid>
      <description>Warning: Please note that this post was written prior to the launch of Windows Identity Foundation. Most of the steps outlined below are no longer accurate nor necessary.
One of the critical elements a company needs to consider when moving to the cloud is how they will leverage their existing identity stores. Most companies have made significant investments in various identity solutions (i.e. providing for SSO, identity consolidation, federating with partners, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Azure in the Real World</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/09/windows-azure-in-the-real-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2009 15:39:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/09/windows-azure-in-the-real-world/</guid>
      <description>Last week I presented at the Wisconsin .NET Users Group for the first time, along with Joseph Paradi. I had a great time, and I really appreciate the hospitality of the group - great facility, attentive audience, and excellent questions. The title of our talk was Windows Azure in the Real World; here&amp;rsquo;s the abstract for the presentation:
   Does this sound familiar? Your boss is asking about cloud computing and Windows Azure, but you&amp;rsquo;re not sure how to separate the hype from the reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting ready for the &#39;Race to Market Challenge&#39;</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/09/getting-ready-for-the-race-to-market-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2009 03:23:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/09/getting-ready-for-the-race-to-market-challenge/</guid>
      <description>I am really excited about The Race to Market Challenge, sponsored by the Windows Mobile team. Nothing motivates me like a challenge that promises great prizes and glory - especially when the prize is a Microsoft Surface!
If that&amp;rsquo;s not enough to get you pumped up about developing a killer application, what will?
I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to build a mobile application myself (two, actually), and consequently needed to make sure that I had my development environment setup appropriately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Azure Migration Wizard</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/09/sql-azure-migration-wizard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2009 03:29:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/09/sql-azure-migration-wizard/</guid>
      <description>In my opinion, SQL Azure is the &amp;ldquo;secret sauce&amp;rdquo; of the Windows Azure Platform. Through SQL Azure, you have the ability to store your data in a true cloud-based relational database. It&amp;rsquo;s as simple as deploying your database to SQL Azure and updating your connection string to point to the new database - done! I think this really provides a core differentiator between the Windows Azure Platform and other cloud vendors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Architecting Your Data Access Layer with the Entity Framework</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/06/architecting-your-data-access-layer-with-the-entity-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2009 17:57:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/06/architecting-your-data-access-layer-with-the-entity-framework/</guid>
      <description>I had the pleasure to co-present with one of my fellow evangelists, Dave Bost, on architecting and developing with the ADO.NET Entity Framework this week. I focused on application architecture topics while Dave focused on developing applications.
I think we can all agree – and if not, please let me know why – that the Entity Framework provides some awesome capabilities – mapping your conceptual schema to your data schema, isolation from the relational database and database schema, change tracking and identity resolution, full query comprehension and optimization, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stratus: Tamer of Clouds</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/06/stratus-tamer-of-clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2009 13:33:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/06/stratus-tamer-of-clouds/</guid>
      <description>Many of you probably recall that I used to work for Statera, a Microsoft partner headquartered back in Colorado. Great company, and great people. It was a hard decision to leave them.
I recently learned that Statera has been investing a lot of time and energy in developing some cool applications using our Azure Services Platform. In particular, Statera built an engine running in Windows Azure that integrations Microsoft CRM Online and SharePoint Online (both of which are part of Microsoft’s Business Productivity Online Suite, or BPOS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Architecture for Enterprises</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/06/.net-architecture-for-enterprises/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 16:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/06/.net-architecture-for-enterprises/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I gave a talk on .NET architecture to a very large customer here in Illinois (in case you’re interested, I had to drive down to Bloomington, IL. to visit them). The description of the talk was pretty bland – “Overview of application architecture for medium to large scale applications.” – so I tried to spice it up a bit. Here’s the presentation:
.NET Architecture for Enterprises
Ultimately, my goal in this talk was to address the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Commerce Server book is now available!</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/05/the-commerce-server-book-is-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2009 15:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/05/the-commerce-server-book-is-now-available/</guid>
      <description>Update (5/31/09) - as Glen notes in the below comment, you can order the book through an English language site. Please seen the instructions in on his blog (http://www.software-smith.com/csbook.html) or go directly here for the site (still a little German, but it&amp;rsquo;s easier to follow in English).
The first – and only – book on Commerce Server 2007 is now available! (Here’s the translated version, thanks to Microsoft Translator - http://bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running a PHP application on Windows Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/03/running-a-php-application-on-windows-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2009 22:31:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/03/running-a-php-application-on-windows-azure/</guid>
      <description>I recently returned from MIX09 – what a fantastic event! So many great things were announced; so many that there’s no way I can list them all here. Please visit http://live.visitmix.com/ for access to the keynote videos and all the breakout sessions. I would also recommend reading the day one recap and the day two recap.
One of the major announcements was new capabilities for the Windows Azure CTP. This includes the support for FastCGI, Full Trust, and Geo-location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Commerce Server 2007 book lives!</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/02/the-commerce-server-2007-book-lives/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2009 21:32:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2009/02/the-commerce-server-2007-book-lives/</guid>
      <description>In fact, not only is it alive, but it’s thriving!
Please take a look at an announcement recently made by Glen (Software) Smith announcing that the Commerce Server 2007 book is finished. You may (or may not) recall that this book was originally going to be published by Wiley (aka Wrox), but that it was cancelled for a number of reasons. Consequently, efforts on the book essentially stalled until Glen stepped up last fall and volunteered to see it through fruition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking to explore the Cloud? Then join your community!</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2008/12/looking-to-explore-the-cloud-then-join-your-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2008 20:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2008/12/looking-to-explore-the-cloud-then-join-your-community/</guid>
      <description>This past Tuesday was the inaugural meeting of the Windows Azure Cloud Computing User Group in Chicago, IL. The mission of this new user group is to provide a forum for developers and architects to discuss Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s vision of Software + Services (S+S), and in particular the Azure Services Platform. This user group is sponsored by Neudesic, and the presenter for the first meeting was Bryce Calhoun, Director at Neudesic. Despite the snow and difficult driving conditions, the meeting was well attended by many members of the local community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Multi-Enterprise Business Applications on the Azure Services Platform</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2008/11/building-multi-enterprise-business-applications-on-the-azure-services-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 03:07:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2008/11/building-multi-enterprise-business-applications-on-the-azure-services-platform/</guid>
      <description>I had the honor and privilege to present with Jack Greenfield at PDC2008 this past week. We discussed our use of the Azure Services Platform - the new Microsoft cloud services layer recently announced at PDC2008 - to build Multi-Enterprise Business Applications (MEBAs). As Jack says in the presentation, the Azure Services Platform has the potential to bring about a resurgence on business-to-business (B2B) in a way that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been possible before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PDC 2008 is coming …</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2008/10/pdc-2008-is-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2008 02:35:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2008/10/pdc-2008-is-coming/</guid>
      <description>… and I can’t wait!
For the last two months I’ve been working on a project that uses the “Windows Cloud OS” and “Cloud Services”, and I can’t wait until we disclose all the details at PDC 2008. Expect to see a significant amount of details regarding this cloud computing project as we get closer and closer to PDC.
In the meantime, enjoy a sneak peak at the work done by one of our ad agencies – can you feel the excitement?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Windows From a Bootable USB Drive</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2008/09/installing-windows-from-a-bootable-usb-drive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 21:23:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2008/09/installing-windows-from-a-bootable-usb-drive/</guid>
      <description>I find myself doing this over and over again, so I figured it would be worthwhile to post. Below you’ll find a really useful way for installing a Windows O/S from a bootable USB device. I am particularly dependent on USB drives, as I have a Lenovo X61 Tablet that doesn’t have a CD/DVD-ROM (unless I’m docked, but I’m hardly in the office).
A couple of notes:
 This assumes you’re running Windows Vista or Windows Server 2008 I’ve tested by installing the following O/S’s: Windows XP SP3, Windows Vista, and Windows Server 2008 You must have a machine capable of booting from a USB drive  Without further ado, here are the steps:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Illinois, Indiana, and Wisconsin User Groups</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2008/04/illinois-indiana-and-wisconsin-user-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2008 14:20:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2008/04/illinois-indiana-and-wisconsin-user-groups/</guid>
      <description>As I am new to Illinois, I recently started looking around to find out about some of the local user groups. My friend and colleague, Dave Bost (developer evangelist and co-host of The Thirsty Developer), recently sent me the following list of user groups in Illinois, Indiana, and Wisconsin. I&amp;rsquo;m not yet sure if this is an exhaustive list or if I&amp;rsquo;m missing some key groups. Please let me know if I&amp;rsquo;m missing any.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing a relationship with Twitter ...</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2008/04/developing-a-relationship-with-twitter-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2008 19:52:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2008/04/developing-a-relationship-with-twitter-.../</guid>
      <description>I know that Twitter is nothing new and that many of you are already using it, but until recently I had managed to resist. However, upon joining Microsoft and getting to know my evangelist peers, I found Twitter to be a great way to both keep in touch and coordinate with my friends and coworkers. Furthermore, having recently moved from Colorado to Illinois, I found that Twitter is also a great way to keep in touch with distant and remote friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Windows Server 2008</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2008/04/installing-windows-server-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2008 02:21:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2008/04/installing-windows-server-2008/</guid>
      <description>I have long been a proponent of working and developing in an environment that matches your production systems. I&amp;rsquo;ve found that developing on the same O/S takes away a lot of the unknowns and guess work that occurs when you deploy from a traditional workstation O/S (like XP or Vista) to a server O/S (like Windows Server 2003 or 2008). Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, Windows XP and Vista are fantastic O/S&amp;rsquo;s and appropriate for all kinds of development; yet, when you&amp;rsquo;re working with products like BizTalk, SharePoint, or Commerce Server, it make sense to use the same server O/S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intel Wireless WiFi Link 4965AGN on a Dell D830 running Windows Server 2008 EE x64</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2008/04/intel-wireless-wifi-link-4965agn-on-a-dell-d830-running-windows-server-2008-ee-x64/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2008 19:56:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2008/04/intel-wireless-wifi-link-4965agn-on-a-dell-d830-running-windows-server-2008-ee-x64/</guid>
      <description>Today I decided to install the x64 version of Windows Server 2008 EE w/ Hyper-V on my Dell D830 laptop. I will post about the experience later (it was awesome!); for now, I want to specifically mention how I was able to get the wireless working.
I should have done my due diligence prior to installing Windows Server 2008, but I like to live dangerously! After the installation was complete (which was simple and fast), I noticed that the wireless adapter was not installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update on the Commerce Server book</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2008/04/update-on-the-commerce-server-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2008 22:52:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2008/04/update-on-the-commerce-server-book/</guid>
      <description>I have been meaning to post an update on the book, but with the new job and move to Illinois it&amp;rsquo;s been difficult to find the time. Since Max mentioned on his blog that the Professional Commerce Server book to be published by Wiley (aka Wrox) has been canceled, I think it&amp;rsquo;s appropriate for me to take the time and add a few details.
Fundamentally, the book was canceled because it was not completed in the allotted timeframe (nor the extended timeframe).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traveling to Las Vegas tomorrow for MIX08</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2008/03/traveling-to-las-vegas-tomorrow-for-mix08/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2008 03:02:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2008/03/traveling-to-las-vegas-tomorrow-for-mix08/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll be in Las Vegas again tomorrow to attend MIX08. In it&amp;rsquo;s third year, MIX is an opportunity to learn about Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s strategy surrounding the future of the web, the latest Microsoft web technologies, rich user experiences, and Vista and IE8 forecasts. It&amp;rsquo;s a great event for technical strategists, creative designers, and technical decision makers. This year, MIX will explore the following:
  High-fidelity commerce, content, media, services and security</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My New Job: Architect Evangelist for Microsoft</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2008/02/my-new-job-architect-evangelist-for-microsoft/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2008 10:09:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2008/02/my-new-job-architect-evangelist-for-microsoft/</guid>
      <description>I recently accepted a job as an Architect Evangelist for Microsoft, working with the central region Developer &amp;amp; Platform Evangelism (DPE) team out of Downers Grove, IL. I am extremely excited - this is a dream come true! I&amp;rsquo;ve spent most of my career as a IT consultant largely focused on Microsoft technologies, and I think this role will really allow me to focus on my interests and passions.
The story behind how I first learned about the role, and how I came to get an offer, is long and (probably) pretty boring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the UpdateProgress to lock down controls in the browser</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2008/01/using-the-updateprogress-to-lock-down-controls-in-the-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2008 03:51:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2008/01/using-the-updateprogress-to-lock-down-controls-in-the-browser/</guid>
      <description>Finally, back to some writing some code! Between writing my book and some of my more recent projects, I haven&amp;rsquo;t had a chance to write a lot of code.
I&amp;rsquo;m currently porting a web-based timesheet application to an ASP.NET AJAX Futures Web Application with the .NET Framework 3.5. In writing the application, I&amp;rsquo;m trying to adhere to a number of practices:
  Separation of concerns
  Test driven development (TDD) to support changing business requirements</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Statera blogger - Ryan McCutchen</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/12/another-statera-blogger-ryan-mccutchen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2007 16:24:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/12/another-statera-blogger-ryan-mccutchen/</guid>
      <description>I just recently discovered that Ryan McCutchen, a colleague of mine here at Statera, started blogging last month. In this past month he has already put together a number of excellent posts discussing MOSS from an information worker, architect, and end-user perspective.
Two posts that jumped out at me:
  Starting the WSS Search Service - I encountered this problem myself, recently. Too bad I hadn&amp;rsquo;t read this post first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the Audit Policy to diagnose security problems</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/12/using-the-audit-policy-to-diagnose-security-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 22:16:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/12/using-the-audit-policy-to-diagnose-security-problems/</guid>
      <description>A neat trick to help you diagnose troublesome security problems. Modify your the audit settings for process tracking, so that successes and failures are logged in your Security log.
 Go to Start -&amp;gt; Run. Type: gpedit.msc Expand Local Computer Policy -&amp;gt; Computer Configuration -&amp;gt; Windows Settings -&amp;gt; Security Settings -&amp;gt; Local Policies -&amp;gt; Audit Policy.  4. Review the &amp;ldquo;Audit process tracking&amp;rdquo; policy. 5. Right-click the &amp;ldquo;Audit process tracking&amp;rdquo; policy, and select Properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Certified Architect (MCA) posts</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/11/microsoft-certified-architect-mca-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2007 04:24:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/11/microsoft-certified-architect-mca-posts/</guid>
      <description>Joe Shirey, an Architect Evangelist for Microsoft, has posted an eight-part series that discusses the Microsoft Certified Architect (MCA) program. If you&amp;rsquo;re like me and have spent time reviewing the Microsoft Certified Architect Programs web site, and wanted a more in-depth, personal understanding of the process, you should take the time to read Joe&amp;rsquo;s posts in their entirety. Joe is one of the original participants of the MCA program, and offers a lot of insight into the process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Donate rice and test your vocabulary</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/11/donate-rice-and-test-your-vocabulary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2007 03:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/11/donate-rice-and-test-your-vocabulary/</guid>
      <description>I learned about the FreeRice program from James McGovern&amp;rsquo;s blog post. Not only does it appear to be a worthwhile program, but the it was fun to test my vocabulary.
link
I stopped after providing 500 grains of rice. I realized that my 500 grains wouldn&amp;rsquo;t make a difference unless I also spread the word. So please, dear reader, take a moment and test your own vocabulary!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some great blog posts on Commerce Server 2007</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/11/some-great-blog-posts-on-commerce-server-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2007 20:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/11/some-great-blog-posts-on-commerce-server-2007/</guid>
      <description>There has been some excellent activity by some heavy-weights in the Commerce Server world. Sadly, I haven&amp;rsquo;t been contributing very much on my blog, as I am desperately trying to complete my book.
It started with Søren Spelling Lund&amp;rsquo;s two-part series (and maybe more?) on what it&amp;rsquo;s like developing with Commerce Server 2007.
 Developing with Microsoft Commerce Server 2007 Part 1: Secure By Default     In this post, Søren highlights the high-level of security that has gone into Commerce Server 2007, calling it &amp;ldquo;both a blessing and a curse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>White papers: Migration from Oracle or Sybase to SQL Server 2005</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/11/white-papers-migration-from-oracle-or-sybase-to-sql-server-2005/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2007 19:32:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/11/white-papers-migration-from-oracle-or-sybase-to-sql-server-2005/</guid>
      <description>Just noticed these two gems (again from the MSDN Architecture Center):
Guide to Migrating from Oracle to SQL Server 2005
Summary: &amp;ldquo;This white paper explores challenges that arise when you migrate from an Oracle 7.3 database or later to SQL Server 2005. It describes the implementation differences of database objects, SQL dialects, and procedural code between the two platforms. The entire migration process using SQL Server Migration Assistant for Oracle (SSMA Oracle) is explained in depth, with a special focus on converting database objects and PL/SQL code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Architectural resources from MSFT</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/11/architectural-resources-from-msft/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2007 15:58:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/11/architectural-resources-from-msft/</guid>
      <description>I have recently been scouring MSFT resources for information related to architecture and the role of enterprise architects, and I have found two resources that I wanted to highlight:
MSDN Architecture Center
This is a great central hub for architectural information related to MSFT technologies, platforms, and products. There are also a number of excellent architects that deal with topics such as service oriented architecture (SOA), Software + Services (S+S, SaaS), security, enterprise architecture, agile development, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aspiring Architects: Four 100-Level Webcasts</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/11/aspiring-architects-four-100-level-webcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2007 19:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/11/aspiring-architects-four-100-level-webcasts/</guid>
      <description>I only recently noticed a four-part series of MSFT webcasts focused on aspiring architects, hosted by Mohammad Akif and Dave Remmer. I found these links after visiting the blog of Hanu Kommalapati, an MSFT architect evangelist. He links to the aspiring architects webcasts himself, as well as Mohammad&amp;rsquo;s blog.
Here are links to the webcasts, as well as some high-level notes on the various topics discussed.
Note: you may think that these webcasts would focus on architecture from the MSFT perspective, but really the presenters do a great job of staying mostly agnostic to technology and platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated Silverlight Hangman Application</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/11/updated-silverlight-hangman-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2007 22:54:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/11/updated-silverlight-hangman-application/</guid>
      <description>It only took me two or three months, but I finally updated my Silverlight Hangman application. It was originally written an earlier version of Silverlight 1.1 alpha, and I hadn&amp;rsquo;t taken the time to update it.
The only things I had to do was switch out the Silverlight.js file and change the value of &amp;ldquo;Hidden&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Collapsed&amp;rdquo; for the &amp;ldquo;Visibility&amp;rdquo; property of objects. Otherwise I was able to use the same files in the Beta 2 version of Visual Studio 2008.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSDN Masters Series Event: Silverlight</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/11/msdn-masters-series-event-silverlight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2007 14:59:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/11/msdn-masters-series-event-silverlight/</guid>
      <description>Last Monday, three of us from Statera (Troy Hall, Colin McGraw, and myself) presented on the topic of Silverlight at the first MSDN Masters Series presentations in Denver, CO. This event was hosted by Joe Shirey, an architect evangelist for MSFT, and was geared towards technical folks at the 200-300 level.
We presented the following three sessions over the course of four hours:
  Programming Silverlight (Wade Wegner) 2: ASP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting the Commerce Server 2007 MOM 2005 Pack for OpsMgr 2007</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/10/converting-the-commerce-server-2007-mom-2005-pack-for-opsmgr-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2007 21:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/10/converting-the-commerce-server-2007-mom-2005-pack-for-opsmgr-2007/</guid>
      <description>Note: For those of you that want to skip the explanation, and simply get a converted management pack for Commerce Server 2007, scroll down to download a MOM 2005 pack converted for OpsMgr 2007 for Commerce Server 2007.
I previously blogged about Commerce Server 2007 and Operational Monitoring, and indicated that there is no native OpsMgr 2007 pack for Commerce Server 2007 (although there will be one some day). For now, we have to convert the MOM 2005 pack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows XP Professional - 96 updates!</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/09/windows-xp-professional-96-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2007 20:34:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/09/windows-xp-professional-96-updates/</guid>
      <description>I installed Windows XP Professional with SP 2 today and was amazed to see this when I ran Windows Update:
96 updates!
It literally took longer to install all the Windows XP updates than it did to install Visual Studio 2005 Team Developer Edition. Amazing!
Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s time for SP 3?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commerce Server 2007 and Operational Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/09/commerce-server-2007-and-operational-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2007 23:50:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/09/commerce-server-2007-and-operational-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>Operational monitoring (OM) is a practice that is sorely underused, in my opinion. OM is a performance and event monitoring practice that allows you to respond to errors and gain insight into machines on your network. Microsoft has two flagship products for operational monitoring: Microsoft Operations Manager (MOM) 2005 and System Center Operations Manager (SCOM) 2007. Through MOM and SCOM you can monitor your Microsoft server products, such as SQL Server, Web Sites, and even Commerce Server 2007.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update: Professional Commerce Server 2007</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/09/update-professional-commerce-server-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2007 19:10:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/09/update-professional-commerce-server-2007/</guid>
      <description>It has been awhile since I last posted about the status of the book Professional Commerce Server 2007, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share some news and exciting developments.
First of all, I am very happy to announce that Tom Schultz has agreed to participate in writing the book and will author a number of chapters. Tom is a senior consultant with the Microsoft Consulting Services (MCS), and is particularly focused on e-commerce and the Commerce Server product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A few tips when using WCF with BizTalk Server 2006 R2</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/09/a-few-tips-when-using-wcf-with-biztalk-server-2006-r2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2007 07:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/09/a-few-tips-when-using-wcf-with-biztalk-server-2006-r2/</guid>
      <description>As I was putting together the demonstration for the talk I&amp;rsquo;m giving tomorrow on BizTalk Server R2 and the WCF Adapters I had to do a few things to get some basic examples working, as this was a brand new virtual environment. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d document some of the actions I had to take.
1. Registering the &amp;ldquo;WCF-BasicHttp&amp;rdquo; adapter.
After creating and deploying an orchestration for use with the &amp;ldquo;WCF-BasicHttp&amp;rdquo; adapter, I received the following error:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a BizTalk Server 2006 R2 (beta 2) development environment</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/09/setting-up-a-biztalk-server-2006-r2-beta-2-development-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2007 22:37:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/09/setting-up-a-biztalk-server-2006-r2-beta-2-development-environment/</guid>
      <description>In preparation for the talk I am giving tomorrow on BizTalk Server R2 and the WCF Adapters, I thought I would post some notes on how to setup and configure a BizTalk Server 2006 R2 development environment. The installation is really quite straightforward. Start with a relatively clean machine (I suggest you use a virtual machine, as these are all beta bits). My (virtual) machine had the following installed before I started the R2 installation:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presenting to the Denver BizTalk User Group</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/09/presenting-to-the-denver-biztalk-user-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2007 21:29:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/09/presenting-to-the-denver-biztalk-user-group/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BizTalk process crashing with eConnect 9 adapter</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/09/biztalk-process-crashing-with-econnect-9-adapter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2007 18:51:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/09/biztalk-process-crashing-with-econnect-9-adapter/</guid>
      <description>I was able to use the XML sample documents that come with eConnect (C:Program FilesMicrosoft Great PlainseConnect9XML Sample DocumentsIncoming) to write some test data into my GP database using the eConnect 9.0 adapters for BizTalk Server 2006. I setup a test environment using the TWO database for Great Plains, and through the adapter was able to insert data. Feeling that I had made some good progress, I shutdown my machine (they are all virtualized environments) and went home for the night.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Hotfix Request Web Submission Form</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/09/microsoft-hotfix-request-web-submission-form/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 16:07:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/09/microsoft-hotfix-request-web-submission-form/</guid>
      <description>Lately it seems that I have had to acquire a lot of hotfixes for Microsoft products. Unfortunately, most of the KB articles don&amp;rsquo;t provide a link to the hotfix, but instead ask you to contact Microsoft Support (via phone) to acquire the hotfix. Kind of a pain!
Fortunately, my friend Rich Finn just passed along this useful link:
Hotfix Request Web Submission Form
Very useful &amp;hellip; no longer will I have to reach out an contact individual escalation engineers I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with in the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simpsonize Us!</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/09/simpsonize-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 14:47:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/09/simpsonize-us/</guid>
      <description>While reading Scott Bellware&amp;rsquo;s blog today, I came across his Simpson&amp;rsquo;s alter ego, courtesy of Simpsonize Me. I had to try it out!
Evidently, here&amp;rsquo;s what I look like as a Simpson&amp;rsquo;s character &amp;hellip; the likeness is uncanny:
Here&amp;rsquo;s me taking a trip to the Quik-E-Mart:
Personally, I think my wife makes a better looking Simpson character than I do:
My daughters also make cute Simpson&amp;rsquo;s characters:
Neat stuff! Give it a try.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Virtual Server 2005 R2 Service Pack 1</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/08/microsoft-virtual-server-2005-r2-service-pack-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2007 05:46:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/08/microsoft-virtual-server-2005-r2-service-pack-1/</guid>
      <description>Somehow I missed the announcement that SP1 was released for Virtual Server 2005 R2. Given that I run nearly all my development (and some non-development) environments on R2, I&amp;rsquo;m surprised I didn&amp;rsquo;t catch wind of SP1!
You can download SP1 here: http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?FamilyId=BC49C7C8-4840-4E67-8DC4-1E6E218ACCE4&amp;amp;displaylang=en. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to note that Vista flavors are listed as supported host operating systems, yet include a &amp;ldquo;non-Production only&amp;rdquo; caveat.
I run Virtual Server 2005 R2 on Vista Business without any problems (well, if you know some tricks).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viewing help files in Windows Vista</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/08/viewing-help-files-in-windows-vista/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2007 02:52:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/08/viewing-help-files-in-windows-vista/</guid>
      <description>I know this is old news, but this post is primarily a reminder to myself &amp;ndash; I keep forgetting! If you try to open a recently downloaded (or installed) help file (*.chm) in Vista, you will get the following message:
 Navigation to the webpage was canceled. Retype the address.
 In order to view the help file, you have to right-click the file, choose Properties, and then click Unblock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deleting Team Project in TFS doesn&#39;t really delete the Team Project</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/08/deleting-team-project-in-tfs-doesnt-really-delete-the-team-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2007 02:46:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/08/deleting-team-project-in-tfs-doesnt-really-delete-the-team-project/</guid>
      <description>One of the things I learned while setting up a virtual Team Foundation Server (TFS) environment is that there are definitely a few &amp;ldquo;gotchas.&amp;rdquo; I encountered one of these while writing up some documentation on how to integrate a Web Application Project (WAP).
Before I began documenting the procedure, I went through and confirmed that everything would work. When I was finished, I figured I would delete the Team Project and start over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a virtual Visual Studio 2005 Team Foundation Server</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/08/setting-up-a-virtual-visual-studio-2005-team-foundation-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2007 02:32:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/08/setting-up-a-virtual-visual-studio-2005-team-foundation-server/</guid>
      <description>Although it has its share of issues, I am a big fan of Visual Studio 2005 Team Foundation Server (known as TFS for short). Often you&amp;rsquo;ll see people only leverage it for a source code repository, but if that&amp;rsquo;s all you are using it for then you are missing out. In addition to storing source code, TFS also supports:
  Code analysis
  Build automation
  Support for continuous integration</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milestone: 100 feed subscribers</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/08/milestone-100-feed-subscribers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2007 18:19:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/08/milestone-100-feed-subscribers/</guid>
      <description>I started blogging as a way of archiving tips-and-tricks I learn everyday so that I can go refer back to the post rather than having to constantly re-learn everything. I have also tried to document ways I have solved various problems and issues that I am confronted with while working with various technologies. I&amp;rsquo;ll admit that, originally, this blog was a purely selfish endeavor - I wasn&amp;rsquo;t motivated by any altruistic reasons, I simply wanted to have a way to archive things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned so that I could refer back to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding a printer in Vista with UAC turned off</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/08/adding-a-printer-in-vista-with-uac-turned-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2007 16:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/08/adding-a-printer-in-vista-with-uac-turned-off/</guid>
      <description>One of the first things I do after installing Vista is turn off UAC (ooh, I can already feel the criticism). I just can abide having to authorize every single action I take on the computer. It&amp;rsquo;s one thing to ask me to confirm a change to IIS or a service running on my machine, but don&amp;rsquo;t make me authorize the deletion of files on the operating system! If I clicked delete and confirmed the deletion, just delete it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warning about Windows Live Writer</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/08/warning-about-windows-live-writer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2007 16:06:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/08/warning-about-windows-live-writer/</guid>
      <description>As those of you who subscribe to this blog&amp;rsquo;s feed have noticed, a place holder record was written into my RSS feed. Having just reinstalled my operating system (I have switched back to Vista Business once again), I was configuring my Windows Live Writer for this blog. If you click View &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Update Weblog Style you will be asked the following:
Just say No!
If you click Yes it will post the following placeholder on your blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>System.Net.WebException when issuing more than two concurrent WebRequest&#39;s</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/08/system.net.webexception-when-issuing-more-than-two-concurrent-webrequests/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2007 18:40:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/08/system.net.webexception-when-issuing-more-than-two-concurrent-webrequests/</guid>
      <description>I got caught up yesterday with a problem I should have recognized right away, but for whatever reason I didn&amp;rsquo;t put the pieces together until it was pointed out by one of my co-workers.
I was writing a BizTalk Server 2006 orchestration that, amongst other things, sends a request to a remote server. The remote server has an application installed that accesses these requests and initiates a few local (and unimportant) processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warning: the CID values for both test machines are the same</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/08/warning-the-cid-values-for-both-test-machines-are-the-same/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2007 21:48:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/08/warning-the-cid-values-for-both-test-machines-are-the-same/</guid>
      <description>I came across a frustrating interesting problem today where the BizTalk Server 2006 Configuration wizard would fail every time I applied a new configuration.
Unlike a typical BizTalk developer environment (which usually consists of BizTalk and SQL Server on the same machine), this environment consisted of two separate machines: one BizTalk Server 2006 and one SQL Server 2005 (i.e. the BizTalk databases are stored on the SQL Server). Additionally, this is a virtual environment and both machines were cloned from the same base Windows Server 2003 R2 template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commerce Server 2007 Development Environments</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/08/commerce-server-2007-development-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2007 16:19:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/08/commerce-server-2007-development-environments/</guid>
      <description>I often get asked about how development environments should be configured and what practices should be implemented when building a Commerce Server 2007 solution. I have found this to be a difficult question to answer, as everyone has their own preferences and &amp;ldquo;best-practices&amp;rdquo; when it comes to development environments. Additionally, we are often constrained by the following variables:
 Relative importance placed on time, cost, and quality Available development and QA skills Software development methodology Scope and function of the application  Over my career I&amp;rsquo;ve come up with a number of things I try to have when building a Commerce Server solution (or any enterprise-level application).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More details on the Commerce Server roadmap and CSID</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/08/more-details-on-the-commerce-server-roadmap-and-csid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2007 02:35:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/08/more-details-on-the-commerce-server-roadmap-and-csid/</guid>
      <description>Earlier today I learned about the new partnership between Microsoft and Cactus Commerce through some press releases, but finally some official announcements come from the Commerce Server product team.
Ryan Donovan has blogged on both the Commerce Server product roadmap and the new Commerce Server Information Desk (CSID) program: Official Announcements: Commerce Server Product Roadmap &amp;amp; Information Desk Program. Here are some of the things I took away from the post:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exciting Commerce Server News</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/08/exciting-commerce-server-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2007 19:46:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/08/exciting-commerce-server-news/</guid>
      <description>Some really interesting news on the Commerce Server front today &amp;hellip;
Cactus Commerce Signs a Global Agreement With Microsoft Corp. for Electronic Commerce
 &amp;ldquo;Cactus Commerce, a software and services company, today announced it has signed an agreement with Microsoft Corporation to drive product development, partner ecosystem development, marketing, services and support of the Commerce Server platform. The long-term strategic partnership reinforces both companies’ continued focus, investment and commitment to lead innovation for the e-commerce marketplace on a global scale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commerce Server Staging error: Operation must use an updateable query</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/07/commerce-server-staging-error-operation-must-use-an-updateable-query/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2007 20:37:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/07/commerce-server-staging-error-operation-must-use-an-updateable-query/</guid>
      <description>I encountered an error today while setting up a project within the Commerce Server Staging. I haven&amp;rsquo;t encountered it before, which leads me to believe that I must have done something abnormal on my development virtual machine.
 Commerce Server Staging (CSS) is a service that allows you to synchronize content and data between many separate environments. Utilizing CSS, you can reliably update both Web content and business data from the source to one or more destinations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a Silverlight development environment</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/07/setting-up-a-silverlight-development-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2007 15:17:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/07/setting-up-a-silverlight-development-environment/</guid>
      <description>This weekend I spent some time playing with Silverlight and Orcas. Needless to say, I am very impressed with both. Here&amp;rsquo;s a sample Hangman application I created in about three hours.
I thought I&amp;rsquo;d go ahead and document the steps I took when I setup my development environment. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to come back here and update the content, so that it stays pertinent as updates are released.
Setting up a Silverlight development environment</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates to the Hangman application</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/07/updates-to-the-hangman-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2007 21:08:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/07/updates-to-the-hangman-application/</guid>
      <description>I had no idea that this game would be so popular! Despite the crappy graphics, it&amp;rsquo;s been referred half a dozen times, and received almost 300 unique hits in the last 24-hours. Pretty amazing!
Here&amp;rsquo;s the link to Hangman. Give it a try. Here&amp;rsquo;s the original Hangman announcement.
There have been a few updates to the original program, including:
  Includes the definition of the word; calls a .NET web service that parses a web response from Dictionary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hangman application built on Silverlight and WPF</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/07/hangman-application-built-on-silverlight-and-wpf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2007 22:49:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/07/hangman-application-built-on-silverlight-and-wpf/</guid>
      <description>Unfortunately I don&amp;rsquo;t have enough time at the moment to write-up a full post that outlines how this works (we have friends coming over for dinner), but I wanted to at least share my very first attempt at a Silverlight and WPF web application.
Check out Hangman!
It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty slick (albeit graphically retarded) Silverlight application. It uses Microsoft Silverlight 1.1 Alpha (for Windows), and I built it on the work I did devising a strategy to (consistently) win hangman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silverlight: &#34;Error Invoking Service&#34; when calling a web service</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/07/silverlight-error-invoking-service-when-calling-a-web-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2007 21:24:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/07/silverlight-error-invoking-service-when-calling-a-web-service/</guid>
      <description>I was writing a Silverlight application today, when I came across the following error when trying to invoke a web service method from my Silverlight project:
   &amp;ldquo;Error invoking service&amp;rdquo;
 After digging around a little bit, I noticed the following above my web method:
   // To allow this Web Service to be called from script, using ASP.NET AJAX, uncomment the following line.
// [System.Web.Script.Services.ScriptService]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devising a strategy to (consistently) win Hangman: Part I</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/07/devising-a-strategy-to-consistently-win-hangman-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2007 02:28:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/07/devising-a-strategy-to-consistently-win-hangman-part-i/</guid>
      <description>Edit: Try my own version of Hangman, written with Silverlight and WPF!
In an effort to distract myself from more productive endeavors, I started playing Hangman on The Free Dictionary Web site today. They have an outstanding plugin that you can also add to your Google homepage (which is actually how I discovered it). The interface allows you to simply type the letter into the guess box (if you look below you&amp;rsquo;ll see that my last guess was the letter &amp;ldquo;G&amp;rdquo;), and it updates it as you go:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to automatically and recursively delete empty directories</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/07/how-to-automatically-and-recursively-delete-empty-directories/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2007 19:18:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/07/how-to-automatically-and-recursively-delete-empty-directories/</guid>
      <description>Years ago I made a serious mistake when I installed, and briefly used, iTunes &amp;ndash; I gave it the ability to reorganize my music folders! Since then, all my nicely organized and sorted directories of (legally obtained) digital music have been disorganized and confused.
For example, I used to have a directory named &amp;ldquo;U2&amp;rdquo; where all my music for the group U2 was stored. However, iTunes decided that my organization structure was too simple, and broke it out into folders derived from the contributing artists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharing photos with family and friends</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/07/sharing-photos-with-family-and-friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2007 17:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/07/sharing-photos-with-family-and-friends/</guid>
      <description>My cousin Kai just got married yesterday in Maine. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to make it, but my parents and sister were able to fly up and attend. By all accounts, it was a fantastic wedding and I wish we could have made it, but with a month old baby (not to mention her two-year-old sister) we just didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like we could handle the trip. And, given the multiple layovers and missed flights my parents encountered along the way, I think we made the right choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commerce Server in the headlines: 07/08/2007 - 07/14/2007</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/07/commerce-server-in-the-headlines-07/08/2007-07/14/2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2007 14:51:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/07/commerce-server-in-the-headlines-07/08/2007-07/14/2007/</guid>
      <description>It was a slower-than-normal week in the world of Commerce Server; that is, slow for everyone except Max. The man is a Commerce Server animal!
The general slowness and lack of blog posts can probably be attributed to the Worldwide Partner Conference in Denver, CO., this past week. Lots of activity. Unfortunately, I was unable to attend. I&amp;rsquo;ve been swamped with BizTalk projects and dirty diapers.
Here&amp;rsquo;s what I read regarding Commerce Server this past week &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google says &#34;We&#39;re sorry ...&#34;</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/07/google-says-were-sorry-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2007 01:33:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/07/google-says-were-sorry-.../</guid>
      <description>I was performing an advanced search on Google Blog Search (posts that include &amp;ldquo;commerce server 2007&amp;rdquo; over the past week) when allow of a sudden I started getting the following error:
Que?! What is it with me and search engines?!
Something very similar happened awhile back when I was searching Yahoo. I got the infamous &amp;ldquo;error 999&amp;rdquo;, which evidently is most often caused by bandwidth limiting that Yahoo! invokes to prevent DoS (Denial of Service) attacks and automated processes that overload their systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring and Testing a Windows Mobile 5.0 Development Environment</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/07/configuring-and-testing-a-windows-mobile-5.0-development-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2007 08:58:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/07/configuring-and-testing-a-windows-mobile-5.0-development-environment/</guid>
      <description>So, I&amp;rsquo;ve finally joined the 21st century, and purchased a Samsung Blackjack. After waiting a two agonizing days, it finally arrived. Man, it&amp;rsquo;s a beauty!
I&amp;rsquo;ll spare you a review of all it&amp;rsquo;s features (this is covered in agonizing detail elsewhere), but there are a couple tidbits I&amp;rsquo;d like to share.
The Blackjack runs Windows Mobile 5.0 with the Messaging and Security Feature Pack. One of the neatest features that this supports is Exchange ActiveSync w/ Direct Push Technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commerce Server in the headlines: 07/01/2007 - 07/07/2007</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/07/commerce-server-in-the-headlines-07/01/2007-07/07/2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2007 21:18:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/07/commerce-server-in-the-headlines-07/01/2007-07/07/2007/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to start posting an aggregation of notable Commerce Server blog and forum postings. I&amp;rsquo;ve never found that Google or Technorati do a great job of searching or summarizing blog topic discussions, so I&amp;rsquo;ll try to do my best to relate what&amp;rsquo;s going on in the Commerce Server community. Mostly, these posts come from people listed in my Commerce Server blogroll, as well as the Commerce Server forums.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BizTalk Server 2006 eConnect Adapters for Great Plains 9.0</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/07/biztalk-server-2006-econnect-adapters-for-great-plains-9.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2007 17:34:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/07/biztalk-server-2006-econnect-adapters-for-great-plains-9.0/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve started working on a project that integrates into Great Plains 9.0 using eConnect. Not having done this using BizTalk Server 2006, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d document some of my observations and the steps I took.
To begin, I was able to get eConnect for GP (en_econnect_for_gp.zip) through my MSDN subscription. If you have Great Plains 9.0, then you should be able to get your hands on this package. When you unzip the package, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice two files:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resolving the BizTalk Server 2006 warning that dependencies cannot be found</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/07/resolving-the-biztalk-server-2006-warning-that-dependencies-cannot-be-found/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2007 15:32:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/07/resolving-the-biztalk-server-2006-warning-that-dependencies-cannot-be-found/</guid>
      <description>I just recently started a new BizTalk Server 2006 project in which I created a custom pipeline component to assist in the compression and decompression of messages. The plan is to have a receive location monitor a folder via the File adapter, and when a zip file is uploaded via FTP from a 3rrd party process, the receive location will use the custom pipeline component , via a receive pipeline, to decompress the file and publish the message to the MessageBox.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem with the Commerce Server 2007 SP1 Installation</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/06/problem-with-the-commerce-server-2007-sp1-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2007 19:23:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/06/problem-with-the-commerce-server-2007-sp1-installation/</guid>
      <description>As was announced yesterday, Service Pack 1 has been released for Commerce Server 2007. This service pack includes support for Windows Vista, the ability to create web application projects in Visual Studio 2005, performance and security enhancements, and a slew of bug fixes.
I have detailed the process for installing SP1 and upgrading your CS sites in the following posts: Commerce Server 2007 Service Pack 1 (SP1) Walkthrough and Commerce Server 2007 Upgrade Wizard (post SP1 install) Walkthrough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commerce Server 2007 Upgrade Wizard (post SP1 install) Walkthrough</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/06/commerce-server-2007-upgrade-wizard-post-sp1-install-walkthrough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2007 18:33:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/06/commerce-server-2007-upgrade-wizard-post-sp1-install-walkthrough/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post, I detailed the process for installing the Commerce Server 2007 SP1. In this post, I have created a walkthrough for the Commerce Server 2007 Upgrade Wizard. The upgrade wizard should be run for all of your Commerce Server 2007 sites immediately after you have installed SP1. So, before you begin this process, be sure you have successfully installed SP1.
(Note: I created this walkthrough, along with verbose screen shots and text, largely for documentation I am delivering to clients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ClickOnce Deployment and the Commerce Server 2007 Business Management Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/06/clickonce-deployment-and-the-commerce-server-2007-business-management-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2007 02:50:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/06/clickonce-deployment-and-the-commerce-server-2007-business-management-applications/</guid>
      <description>As a Commerce Server developer, you are bound to come across a situation where the smart client business user applications (e.g. the Catalog Manager, Catalog and Inventory Schema Manager, Customer and Orders Manager, and Marketing Manager) do not satisfy a business requirement, need to reflect a company&amp;rsquo;s brand or style, or your business users simply want it changed.
Fortunately, you can get the full C# source code for the business user applications (except for the Catalog and Inventory Schema Manager; see Max&amp;rsquo;s comment in this thread) through the Commerce Server 2007 Partner SDK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commerce Server 2007 Starter Site installation error: Error importing object data for Transaction Config</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/06/commerce-server-2007-starter-site-installation-error-error-importing-object-data-for-transaction-config/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2007 19:15:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/06/commerce-server-2007-starter-site-installation-error-error-importing-object-data-for-transaction-config/</guid>
      <description>During the installation of the Commerce Server 2007 Starter Site, I received the following error in the Pup.log file:
[10:57:50] Error importing object data for Transaction Config from file C:Documents and SettingsAdministratorLocal SettingsTempTransaction Config 8004E024:COM+ activation failed because the activation could not be completed in the specified amount of time. (Exception from HRESULT: 0x8004E024)  I also saw the following error in the Application Log, written at the exact same time:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two great blogging widgets: ClustrMap and whos.amung.us</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/06/two-great-blogging-widgets-clustrmap-and-whos.amung.us/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2007 00:45:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/06/two-great-blogging-widgets-clustrmap-and-whos.amung.us/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m finally taking the time to highlight two blogging widgets that I have been using on my blog: ClustrMap and whos.amung.us. These aren&amp;rsquo;t the only widgets I use, but of the half-dozen scattered throughout my blog these are (arguably) the least well-known (at least, I don&amp;rsquo;t see them very often).
The first is ClustrMap. ClustrMap is a mapping widget that embeds itself into your blog and visually displays the location of your various visitors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Max Akbar has announced his new Commerce Server training company and Web site</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/06/max-akbar-has-announced-his-new-commerce-server-training-company-and-web-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2007 18:18:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/06/max-akbar-has-announced-his-new-commerce-server-training-company-and-web-site/</guid>
      <description>Max Akbar, Commerce Server expert and former Senior Product Manager for the Commerce Server team, has announced his new training company and web site. Training resources include video tutorials, DVDs, PowerPoint presentations, codes samples, and on-site training. You can find more information on his Web site at http://www.commerceservertraining.com/.
Max recently left Microsoft to consult and train companies using Commerce Server. While this is a huge loss for Microsoft, it is a huge win for the Commerce Server community as there has been a noticeable lack of training resources available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you Yahoo!?  No, can&#39;t say that I do ...</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/06/do-you-yahoo-no-cant-say-that-i-do-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 22:09:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/06/do-you-yahoo-no-cant-say-that-i-do-.../</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip; and here&amp;rsquo;s a good reason why:
Every time I attempt to search, I get the error &amp;ldquo;Sorry, Unable to process request at this time &amp;ndash; error 999.&amp;rdquo; This has been occurring for at least the past 30 minutes. However, I pinged a friend of mine, Brad Younge, and he can search just fine. Quite strange!
A quick search via Google (and no, I&amp;rsquo;ve never received an &amp;ldquo;unable to process request at this time&amp;rdquo; error from Google) shows that a LOT of people have this problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Script the creation of SQL logins and role assignments for Commerce Server 2007</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/06/script-the-creation-of-sql-logins-and-role-assignments-for-commerce-server-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 16:46:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/06/script-the-creation-of-sql-logins-and-role-assignments-for-commerce-server-2007/</guid>
      <description>One of the more manually intense steps in the installation of Commerce Server is setting up the appropriate SQL logins and Database Role User Mapping. This task can easily take 30 - 60 minutes to complete if done manually. Futhermore, it&amp;rsquo;s likely that this is the easiest step to make a mistake, which will cause problems for you down the road.
So, to make this process quicker and less prone to errors, I&amp;rsquo;ve created an SQL script that you can run against your database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Script the creation and assignment of Windows groups for Commerce Server</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/06/script-the-creation-and-assignment-of-windows-groups-for-commerce-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 15:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/06/script-the-creation-and-assignment-of-windows-groups-for-commerce-server/</guid>
      <description>Holy moly, I&amp;rsquo;ve gone script crazy!
Here&amp;rsquo;s another little script that helps with the installation of Commerce Server 2007 (perhaps when I&amp;rsquo;m all done, I&amp;rsquo;ll consolidate them all into an uber-script). This script creates the Business Management Administrator Windows groups, which are used to control authorization roles within the Authorization Manager.
This script creates four Windows groups (CatalogAdminGroup, MarketingAdminGroup, ProfilesAdminGroup, and OrdersAdminGroup) and then assigns users to those groups.
Without further ado, here&amp;rsquo;s the script:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Script permission updates for Commerce Server 2007</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/06/script-permission-updates-for-commerce-server-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 04:21:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/06/script-permission-updates-for-commerce-server-2007/</guid>
      <description>Okay, so here&amp;rsquo;s another useful script.
Commerce Server 2007 requires you to give service accounts write permissions to various files and folders. This script assigns the write permissions to the Catalog Web service, the Temporary ASP.NET folder, and the Windows Temporary folder. These permission allow you to run the Business User applications through the Business Management Web services.
In order to run this script, you must have the XCACLS.vbs file available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add “VS.NET Command Prompt Here” to Windows Explorer</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/06/add-vs.net-command-prompt-here-to-windows-explorer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 02:40:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/06/add-vs.net-command-prompt-here-to-windows-explorer/</guid>
      <description>I was browsing one of my new favorite websites, Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Script Repository, when I came upon the Add &amp;ldquo;Command Prompt Here&amp;rdquo; to Windows Explorer&amp;quot; Web page. This script adds a &amp;ldquo;Command Prompt Here&amp;rdquo; command to the Windows Explorer system menu, so that if you select the command, a command window will open up in the same folder. Nifty, eh? Yes, I know, this has been around for quite awhile and is nothing new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Script the creation of local user accounts for Commerce Server 2007</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/06/script-the-creation-of-local-user-accounts-for-commerce-server-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2007 21:24:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/06/script-the-creation-of-local-user-accounts-for-commerce-server-2007/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest &amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m lazy. I hate doing repetitive things over, and over, and over again. So, while I was going through and installing Commerce Server 2007 on a new virtual machine, I decided to script out the creation of the local user accounts. Before we get to the script, a little background &amp;hellip;
It is recommended that you create multiple accounts to handle the various roles within Commerce Server (such as the four web services, staging, etc).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The database version (C.0.8.40) does not match your reporting services installation.</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/06/the-database-version-c.0.8.40-does-not-match-your-reporting-services-installation./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2007 19:09:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/06/the-database-version-c.0.8.40-does-not-match-your-reporting-services-installation./</guid>
      <description>As I was preparing a new virtual machine for Commerce Server 2007 (one capable of utilizing the Commerce Server Adapters with BizTalk Server 2006 and Data Warehousing), I ran into a problem when configuring SQL Server Reporting Services.
I had taken a virtual machine that I use as my base installation (e.g. Windows Server 2003 R2, IIS, .NET 2.0, Visual Studio 2005, and the SQL Server 2005 Database Engine) and was following the Commerce Server 2007 Pre-install Requirements and Procedures from the Installation Guide when I encoutered the following error:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s your Google rank or page position?</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/06/whats-your-google-rank-or-page-position/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2007 04:17:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/06/whats-your-google-rank-or-page-position/</guid>
      <description>I often find myself curious as to what my rank/position on Google is, given a set of keywords. For example, I know that if I search on my name &amp;ldquo;Wade Wegner&amp;rdquo; this blog comes up second (my personal site being first). However, I sometimes wonder where my blog falls for other keywords, such as &amp;ldquo;commerce server 2007&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;biztalk server 2006&amp;rdquo;.
So, I wrote this little tool to tell me!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The project location is not trusted ...</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/06/the-project-location-is-not-trusted-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2007 21:09:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/06/the-project-location-is-not-trusted-.../</guid>
      <description>Having recently purchased a new server, I found myself configuring and setting up the various virtual machines I use for software development. After I setup my development virtual machine, I moved some of my projects over to the D drive and double-clicked one of the project files. After the IDE opened up, but before the project loaded, I received the following dialog message:
&amp;quot;The project location is not trusted. Running the application may result in security exceptions when it attempts to perform actions which require full trust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oracle for Microsoft Developers, Part II: Setting Up Your Database</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/05/oracle-for-microsoft-developers-part-ii-setting-up-your-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2007 13:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/05/oracle-for-microsoft-developers-part-ii-setting-up-your-database/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I detailed how to setup an Oracle database server on Windows Server 2003 in Oracle for Microsoft Developers, Part I: Installing Oracle 9.2 on Windows Server 2003. Today, I want to step back a little, take a look at some of the conceptual differences between Oracle and SQL Server, and then provide steps you can take to setup an Oracle database that you can use within your applications.
You may be saying to yourself, &amp;ldquo;Why should I care how to setup an Oracle database server and database?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oracle for Microsoft Developers, Part I: Installing Oracle 9.2 on Windows Server 2003</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/05/oracle-for-microsoft-developers-part-i-installing-oracle-9.2-on-windows-server-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2007 03:34:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/05/oracle-for-microsoft-developers-part-i-installing-oracle-9.2-on-windows-server-2003/</guid>
      <description>There comes a time in every Microsoft developers life that he/she will have to work with an Oracle database. I hope that you find this to be a good experience; my experiences have thus far been a mixed bag, mostly because of my own ignorance. Nevertheless, I&amp;rsquo;ve picked up a few things here and there, and figured that it would be worthwhile to post some of the top tips and tricks I&amp;rsquo;ve learned over the years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNC error: XXXXXXX is not accessible. You might not have permission to use this network resource. Access is denied.</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/05/unc-error-xxxxxxx-is-not-accessible.-you-might-not-have-permission-to-use-this-network-resource.-access-is-denied./</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2007 19:30:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/05/unc-error-xxxxxxx-is-not-accessible.-you-might-not-have-permission-to-use-this-network-resource.-access-is-denied./</guid>
      <description>Have you ever received the following error when you tried to access a UNC path?
_XXXXXXX_ is not accessible. You might not have permission to use this network resource. Access is denied.  I found that if I logged into some of our production servers, I was unable to connect to a UNC path on the file server (a different machine), even though I was able to access these resources locally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commerce Server road map and commitment!</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/05/commerce-server-road-map-and-commitment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2007 12:58:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/05/commerce-server-road-map-and-commitment/</guid>
      <description>I awoke to see a very encouraging post from Ryan Donovan on the future of Commerce Server.
Some key points to take away:
  Microsoft is committed to their e-commerce platform, and has no plans to roll Commerce Server into another server product (for those of you who follow, there has been a lot of speculation and rumors about Microsoft not being fully committed to Commerce Server - this really helps to dispel those rumors).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting with the Sysinternals utilities</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/05/troubleshooting-with-the-sysinternals-utilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2007 01:47:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/05/troubleshooting-with-the-sysinternals-utilities/</guid>
      <description>As a consultant, I often have to spend a great deal of time diagnosing issues that are confronting my clients. Over the years I&amp;rsquo;ve used some of the tools available from Sysinternals, but I honestly never put a lot of energy or time into really learning to use them. On my most recent project, however, I&amp;rsquo;ve found them to be tremendously helpful, and I&amp;rsquo;m now a confirmed believer!
There are a number of useful tools available, and I don&amp;rsquo;t profess to have used or mastered them all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commerce Server 2007: BizTalk 2006 Adapter White Papers</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/05/commerce-server-2007-biztalk-2006-adapter-white-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2007 02:41:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/05/commerce-server-2007-biztalk-2006-adapter-white-papers/</guid>
      <description>The Commerce Server team has released four white papers outlining how to use the Commerce Server adapters to export a product catalog, export an inventory catalog, export new orders, and export user profiles. If you are attempting to use the adapters (or even thinking about it), I highly encourage you to take a look at these white papers. If nothing else, they will give you a good overview of how you can make use of these adapter (I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to blog on them for awhile now, but haven&amp;rsquo;t found the time).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new twist to the error: &#34;Unable to enlist in the transaction.&#34;</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/05/a-new-twist-to-the-error-unable-to-enlist-in-the-transaction./</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2007 19:10:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/05/a-new-twist-to-the-error-unable-to-enlist-in-the-transaction./</guid>
      <description>I learned a new twist to the following error message today:
The adapter &amp;quot;SQL&amp;quot; raised an error message. Details &amp;quot;Unable to enlist in the transaction. (Exception from HRESULT: 0x8004D00A)&amp;quot;.  This can occur in a scenario where your BizTalk server attempts to connect to a separate SQL Server database and execute a distributed transaction. In order for this to work the BizTalk server must have the ability to &amp;ldquo;hand-off&amp;rdquo; the transaction to SQL Server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The BizTalk Adapters for Enterprise Applications on Windows Server 2003 64-bit</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/05/the-biztalk-adapters-for-enterprise-applications-on-windows-server-2003-64-bit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2007 21:21:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/05/the-biztalk-adapters-for-enterprise-applications-on-windows-server-2003-64-bit/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned in a previous blog, I&amp;rsquo;ve been setting up BizTalk 2006 in a 64-bit Windows Server 2003 environment. This BizTalk solution communicates to AS/400 and Oracle, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the Microsoft BizTalk Adapters for Enterprise Applications (for Oracle connectivity) as well as Microsoft BizTalk Adapters for Host Systems (for AS/400 DB2 connectivity).
Setting up these adapters has not gone extremely well in the 64-bit O/S (whereas a 32-bit O/S is quite simple to configure).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unable to open shim database version registry key - v2.0.50727.00000.</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/05/unable-to-open-shim-database-version-registry-key-v2.0.50727.00000./</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2007 18:35:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/05/unable-to-open-shim-database-version-registry-key-v2.0.50727.00000./</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve worked with .NET 2.0 long enough, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably come across the following error:
The description for Event ID ( 0 ) in Source ( .NET Runtime ) cannot be found. The local computer may not have the necessary registry information or message DLL files to display messages from a remote computer. You may be able to use the /AUXSOURCE= flag to retrieve this description; see Help and Support for details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding ODBC connections in Windows Server 2003 64-bit</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/05/adding-odbc-connections-in-windows-server-2003-64-bit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2007 15:51:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/05/adding-odbc-connections-in-windows-server-2003-64-bit/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve been deploying a BizTalk 2006 solution to a x64 system and, while BizTalk 2006 itself has no problems, I&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of problems related to the BizTalk Adapters for Host Systems and the BizTalk Adapters for Enterprise Applications. I plan to write a number of posts in the near future discussing these problems (once we have them all resolved). In the meantime, I wanted to share this little tidbit I&amp;rsquo;ve learned about ODBC on 64-bit windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring the Adventure Works catalog for Commerce Server 2007</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/05/configuring-the-adventure-works-catalog-for-commerce-server-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2007 20:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/05/configuring-the-adventure-works-catalog-for-commerce-server-2007/</guid>
      <description>I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share this quick and dirty way to load the Adventure Works catalog into Commerce Server 2007 so that you can use it with the Starter Site. This catalog, along with the Start Site, is a great way to familiarize yourself with well designed catalog and how it interacts with Start Site.
This procedure assumes that you&amp;rsquo;ve downloaded the Starter Site, and unpacked it to the default location. Also, it assumes that you&amp;rsquo;ve setup the Business Management Applications to interact correctly with the Commerce Server web services, which in turn assumes you&amp;rsquo;ve configured security for the web services through Azman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BizTalk 2006 XPath expression gotcha!</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/04/biztalk-2006-xpath-expression-gotcha/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2007 17:22:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/04/biztalk-2006-xpath-expression-gotcha/</guid>
      <description>I built an XPath expression to extract the contents of an XML element. I tested this XPath in a utility I created that executes the expression, and writes the results to the file system. The XPath expression worked perfectly, and returned the contents of the XML element. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick and dirty example &amp;hellip;
My XML file:
&amp;lt;ns0:Example xmlns:ns0=&amp;quot;[http://example/](http://example/)&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;ns0:Contents&amp;gt;1169861&amp;lt;/ns0:Contents&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/ns0:Example&amp;gt;  And my XPath expression:
/*[local-name()=&#39;Example&#39; and namespace-uri()=&#39;http://example/&#39;]/*[local-name()=&#39;Contents&#39; and namespace-uri()=&#39;http://example/&#39;]/text()  (Don&amp;rsquo;t forget the &amp;ldquo;/text()&amp;rdquo; at the end, or you&amp;rsquo;ll get the entire element!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BizTalk deployment errors from Visual Studio 2005</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/04/biztalk-deployment-errors-from-visual-studio-2005/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2007 21:09:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/04/biztalk-deployment-errors-from-visual-studio-2005/</guid>
      <description>So, I was having fun building some Orchestrations and Pipelines in BizTalk 2006, when all of a sudden I started getting some awful errors when I went to deploy from Visual Studio 2005. Here are the errors I received:
Object reference not set to an instance of an object. at Microsoft.BizTalk.Deployment.BizTalkAssembly.GetConnectedPorts(BtsCatalogExplorer explorer, String pipelineFullyQualifiedName) at Microsoft.BizTalk.Deployment.BizTalkAssembly.RemovePortsUsingPipelines() at Microsoft.BizTalk.Deployment.BizTalkAssembly.RemovePipelines() at Microsoft.BizTalk.Deployment.BizTalkAssembly.Remove() at Microsoft.BizTalk.Deployment.BizTalkAssembly.RemoveNamedModule(String server, String database, String assemblyName, String assemblyVersion, String assemblyCulture, String assemblyPublicKeyToken, ApplicationLog log) Unspecified exception: &amp;quot;Object reference not set to an instance of an object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New hosting for blog</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/04/new-hosting-for-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2007 01:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/04/new-hosting-for-blog/</guid>
      <description>I have started hosting this blog in a new location. Unfortunately there were some routing issues, and I think the blog was down for about two or three hours. Those problem has been corrected, and it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t happen again (who would have guessed that the network adapter was defaulted to turn off when not being used).
Hey! I&amp;rsquo;m a software developer, not a systems guru!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Universal Data Link (UDL)</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/04/creating-a-universal-data-link-udl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2007 02:32:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/04/creating-a-universal-data-link-udl/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s often nice, while working with BizTalk (or any other MS product, for that matter) to have UDL files available to allow you to quickly setup your connections to various databases. A UDL file is essentially a file that saves connection information, making it available for future use.
To create a UDL file, follow these steps:
  Open a folder (or use the desktop) and create a new text file (right-click &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; New &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Text Document).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commerce Server 2007 - Inventory Catalog</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/commerce-server-2007-inventory-catalog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2007 21:49:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/commerce-server-2007-inventory-catalog/</guid>
      <description>While scavenging the web for information related to both self-service and inventory catalogs, I came across the following post by Martin: Commerce Server 2007 - Backorderable Products. I think it&amp;rsquo;s a good post showing how to configure your inventory catalog to allow for backorderable items.
I hope to see more posts from Martin in the future!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commerce Server 2007 training resources</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/commerce-server-2007-training-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2007 16:13:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/commerce-server-2007-training-resources/</guid>
      <description>Having problems getting yourself or your team up to speed on Commerce Server? Want to leverage your existing skills in ASP.NET and SQL Server?
As many of you are probably aware, good technical training resources for Commerce Serve 2007 are hard to come by. In no way is this meant to be a criticism of the Commerce Server product team, as they have made every effort to blog and webcast about technical topics and some of the newer features of Commerce Server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming with Commerce Server in two modes: InProc mode and Web Service mode</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/programming-with-commerce-server-in-two-modes-inproc-mode-and-web-service-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2007 02:03:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/programming-with-commerce-server-in-two-modes-inproc-mode-and-web-service-mode/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a concept in Commerce Server (and many other products, for that matter) that&amp;rsquo;s important to understand. There are two ways to go about programming against the core systems (i.e. Catalog, Inventory, Profiles, Orders, and Marketing) in Commerce Server&amp;ndash;InProc mode and Web Service mode. Vinayak, a developer on the Commerce Server team, wrote an excellent blog about this concept (last October) as it relates to the catalog system. There are also some great code examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Max Akbar has agreed to be the technical reviewer!</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/max-akbar-has-agreed-to-be-the-technical-reviewer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2007 13:55:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/max-akbar-has-agreed-to-be-the-technical-reviewer/</guid>
      <description>04/13/2008 - Please see this post for information regarding this book.
I&amp;rsquo;m excited to announce that Max Akbar, senior product manager for the Microsoft Commerce Server team, has agreed to work with me on the book Professional Commerce Server 2007 (for WROX) as the official technical reviewer. This is great news, as Max has an incredible amount of knowledge and experience with the Commerce Server product, which will be invaluable as I write this book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the release of InfinityGL, by rhythmiQ</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/announcing-the-release-of-infinitygl-by-rhythmiq/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2007 03:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/announcing-the-release-of-infinitygl-by-rhythmiq/</guid>
      <description>Ever meet or work with one of those developers who had the whole package? This person intuitively understood the needs of business users, had the ability to consistently deliver top quality code with little or no bugs, and was one of the hands down best technical resources and coders you ever met?
I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with someone like that &amp;ndash; Mike Meadows, a fellow IT professional out here in the greater Denver area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Live Writer (beta)</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/windows-live-writer-beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2007 21:19:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/windows-live-writer-beta/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to a link from Joachim Lykke Andersen&amp;rsquo;s DevTalk blog, I learned about a new blogging tool from Microsoft called &amp;ldquo;Windows Live Writer&amp;rdquo; (beta). Check out the details from the Windows Live Writer team blog.
This seems to be a great tool, and one I believe I&amp;rsquo;ll use religiously. Check it out!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commerce Server 2007 Webcasts and other valuable links</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/commerce-server-2007-webcasts-and-other-valuable-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2007 19:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/commerce-server-2007-webcasts-and-other-valuable-links/</guid>
      <description>While I realize these have been around for awhile, I thought I would post some links to great webcasts discussing different aspects of Commerce Server 2007.
 Commerce Server 2007 Architectural Deep-Dive by David Messner Commerce Server 2007 Data Warehouse by Brian Blum and Alan Faulkner Commerce Server 2007 BizTalk Adapters in Action by Brian Blum and Alan Faulkner Developing with the Commerce Server 2007 Marketing System by Madhur Joshi and David Lott Commerce Server 2007 Product Catalog Deep-dive by Austin Skyles Commerce Server 2007 Overview by Mark Townsend Multi-Channel, Connected Commerce (BTS/CS integration) by Caesar Samsi  These are all great webcasts, and I encourage anyone looking to learn more about CS 2007 to watch them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing the computer name of a BizTalk 2006 server</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/changing-the-computer-name-of-a-biztalk-2006-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2007 16:39:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/changing-the-computer-name-of-a-biztalk-2006-server/</guid>
      <description>I recently found myself in a situation where I had to change the computer name of a machine I had configured as a BizTalk 2006 server. The machine was actually a virtual machine that was going to be used for development, and we made numerous copies for all the developers. Consequently, each developer needed to have a computer with a unique name.
After researching the appropriate way to do this, all I could find were very manual steps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking exam 70-235 tomorrow ... [Passed!]</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/taking-exam-70-235-tomorrow-...-passed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2007 01:34:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/taking-exam-70-235-tomorrow-...-passed/</guid>
      <description>I have been studying for the MS exam 70-235: Developing Business Process and Integration Solutions Using Microsoft BizTalk Server for the past couple months. Finding resources for this exam has been difficult, but I&amp;rsquo;ve found a few that were helpful. I was fortunate enough to take the following two Microsoft courses:
  Course 2933: Developing Business Process and Integration Solutions Using Microsoft BizTalk Server 2006
  Course 2934: Deploying and Managing Business Process and Integration Solutions Using Microsoft BizTalk Server 2006</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to stop the high-pitched noise emitted by Dell Latitudes [Updated]</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/how-to-stop-the-high-pitched-noise-emitted-by-dell-latitudes-updated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2007 14:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/how-to-stop-the-high-pitched-noise-emitted-by-dell-latitudes-updated/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to explain to people how the high-pitched noise emitting from my Dell Latitude D820 (which is a great computer) has been driving me crazy! Indeed, after complaining about this noise, most people actually think I have GONE crazy. But, it turns out that it&amp;rsquo;s actually a known issue. Here&amp;rsquo;s an article published by Dell:
http://support.dell.com/support/topics/global.aspx/support/dsn/en/document?c=us&amp;amp;docid=0A7D5CD2E17F5125E0401E0A55176204&amp;amp;journalid=B141AFF2D12811DA8253D5412E975AB8&amp;amp;l=en&amp;amp;s=gen
Personally, I find it quite humorous that Dell blames the problem on Piezoelectricity, and even goes so far as to link to Wikipedia for more information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professional Commerce Server 2007</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/professional-commerce-server-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2007 19:24:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/professional-commerce-server-2007/</guid>
      <description>I have just closed a deal with Wrox (http://www.wrox.com/) to write a book on Commerce Server 2007!
This book will be part of the Professional series, and entitled Professional Commerce Server 2007. Writing begins next week, and should be completed by the end of Q3, 2007. It should hit store shelves some time in late 2007, early 2008. A long process, yet hopefully very worthwhile!
This book will deal with advanced topics, such as:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the &#34;ODBC Adapter for Oracle Database&#34; in BizTalk 2006</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/using-the-odbc-adapter-for-oracle-database-in-biztalk-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2007 03:57:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/using-the-odbc-adapter-for-oracle-database-in-biztalk-2006/</guid>
      <description>Having used the &amp;ldquo;Microsoft BizTalk Adapters for Host Systems&amp;rdquo; to connect to a DB2 back-end, I thought I was ready for any adapter challenge. Turns out that using the &amp;ldquo;Microsoft BizTalk Adapters for Enterprise Applications&amp;rdquo; to connect to Oracle was a little trickier than I thought it would be.
To start, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out where to find the Oracle adapter! If you read the BizTalk 2006 Pricing and Licensing page (http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to turn off the beep sound in a virtual machine in Virtual Server 2005</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/how-to-turn-off-the-beep-sound-in-a-virtual-machine-in-virtual-server-2005/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2007 14:20:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/how-to-turn-off-the-beep-sound-in-a-virtual-machine-in-virtual-server-2005/</guid>
      <description>Since I use virtual machines (VMs) for development, I often find myself having to turn off the beep service on my VMs, or risk the rather of my neighbors. There are a couple of ways to do this:
  Stop the beep on/off for the particular session. Obviously, the problem with this is that once you restart your machine, the beep service will restart. Nevertheless, you can type the the following at the command line:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring HTTP as a transport protocol in BizTalk 2006</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/configuring-http-as-a-transport-protocol-in-biztalk-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2007 03:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/configuring-http-as-a-transport-protocol-in-biztalk-2006/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a project where we have two independent BizTalk 2006 clusters &amp;ndash; one at the headquarters, and one (actually, a few) at some a remote office. In order to send messages back and forth, we are using HTTP as the transport protocol.
For example, we first query an AS400/DB2 database (via the HOST adapters for BizTalk 2006) through a receive port/location. This is picked up by a subscribing send port, which posts it via HTTP to the remote office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting Directly to the Console via Remote Desktop</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/connecting-directly-to-the-console-via-remote-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2007 00:28:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/connecting-directly-to-the-console-via-remote-desktop/</guid>
      <description>Many applications require (or should have) direct access to the Windows Console, rather than a session on the the Windows Server. I encounter these kind of problems often, as I do all my development on virtual machines (running on Virtual Server 2005 R2) and use Remote Desktop to connect.
In order to accomplish this, call the Remote Desktop application with the following command:
mstsc /console  This will attach the Remote Desktop application directly to the system console, preventing any issues that can result from attaching to a session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring and Integrating Microsoft Office SharePoint Server 2007 and Microsoft Commerce Server 2007</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/configuring-and-integrating-microsoft-office-sharepoint-server-2007-and-microsoft-commerce-server-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2007 18:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/configuring-and-integrating-microsoft-office-sharepoint-server-2007-and-microsoft-commerce-server-2007/</guid>
      <description>One of the most common questions people ask is, how can we integrate Commerce Server 2007 with Microsoft Office SharePoint Server (MOSS) 2007? Well, Henry Winkler, a consultant with Microsoft Consulting Services in Denver whom I&amp;rsquo;ve had the pleasure to work with in the recent past, has written the following white paper:
http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?FamilyId=2AEB1A5E-43B8-483B-8CB2-86C0E82BF0AB&amp;amp;displaylang=en
This whitepaper includes code samples that make it easy to integrate these two products together.
Thank you Henry!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Virtual Server 2005 R2 on Windows Vista [Updated]</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/installing-virtual-server-2005-r2-on-windows-vista-updated/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2007 00:14:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/03/installing-virtual-server-2005-r2-on-windows-vista-updated/</guid>
      <description>I came across a great blog entry today that provided the following script. This script will setup IIS with the proper configuration to allow Virtual Server 2005 R2 to function. Just run this in the command line (or create a batch file) before installing Virtual Server.
start /w pkgmgr /l:log.etw /iu:IIS-WebServerRole;IIS-WebServer;IIS-CommonHttpFeatures;IIS-StaticContent;IIS-DefaultDocument;IIS-DirectoryBrowsing;IIS-HttpErrors;IIS-HttpRedirect;IIS-ApplicationDevelopment;IIS-ASPNET;IIS-NetFxExtensibility;IIS-ASP;IIS-CGI;IIS-ISAPIExtensions;IIS-ISAPIFilter;IIS-ServerSideIncludes;IIS-HealthAndDiagnostics;IIS-HttpLogging;IIS-LoggingLibraries;IIS-RequestMonitor;IIS-HttpTracing;IIS-CustomLogging;IIS-ODBCLogging;IIS-Security;IIS-BasicAuthentication;IIS-WindowsAuthentication;IIS-DigestAuthentication;IIS-ClientCertificateMappingAuthentication;IIS-IISCertificateMappingAuthentication;IIS-URLAuthorization;IIS-RequestFiltering;IIS-IPSecurity;IIS-Performance;IIS-HttpCompressionStatic;IIS-HttpCompressionDynamic;IIS-WebServerManagementTools;IIS-ManagementConsole;IIS-ManagementScriptingTools;IIS-ManagementService;IIS-IIS6ManagementCompatibility;IIS-Metabase;IIS-WMICompatibility;IIS-LegacyScripts;IIS-LegacySnapIn;IIS-FTPPublishingService;IIS-FTPServer;IIS-FTPManagement;WAS-WindowsActivationService;WAS-ProcessModel;WAS-NetFxEnvironment;WAS-ConfigurationAPI  Note: this will pretty much install everything under IIS. I recommend that you either go through and remove some of the above settings, or go in afterwards and do so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Error &#34;This request requires buffering data to succeed.&#34;</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/02/error-this-request-requires-buffering-data-to-succeed./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2007 16:39:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2007/02/error-this-request-requires-buffering-data-to-succeed./</guid>
      <description>If you get the following error with an HTTP send port in BizTalk 2006, you may have an authentication issue:
A message send to adapter &amp;quot;HTTP&amp;quot; on send port &amp;quot;SendPort1&amp;quot; with URI http://localhost/vd/BTSHTTPReceive.dll?QueryString is suspended. Error details: This request requires buffering data to succeed.  Check the following to see if it&amp;rsquo;s the source of the problem:
  Go to the properties of your send port.
  Click on &amp;ldquo;Configure&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; next to your HTTP type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using AI to predict football outcomes</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2006/12/using-ai-to-predict-football-outcomes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2006 00:29:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2006/12/using-ai-to-predict-football-outcomes/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post, I attempted to create a very simple artificial neural network (ANN) to predict the outcome of NFL games. I found that the approach I took was really no better than random guesses, as I had an average accuracy of 50%.
Consequently, I decided upon a different approach. I used the same network architecture, but I added data which allowed the network to make more accurate predictions. This time, I used the following data:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial approach to using AI to predict football outcomes</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2006/12/initial-approach-to-using-ai-to-predict-football-outcomes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2006 20:09:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2006/12/initial-approach-to-using-ai-to-predict-football-outcomes/</guid>
      <description>Note: an updated, more accurate method can be found here.
Over the past few months, I have been playing around with artificial neural networks (ANNs) in C#. For those of you unfamiliar with ANNs, it is an attempt to programmatically reproduce the way the brain processes data.
Below is a simple ANN architecture:
On the left we have inputs (i.e. data), and on the right we have an output (i.e. the outcome).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up networking over wireless with Virtual Server 2005 R2</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2006/11/setting-up-networking-over-wireless-with-virtual-server-2005-r2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2006 22:09:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2006/11/setting-up-networking-over-wireless-with-virtual-server-2005-r2/</guid>
      <description>I recently had to configure a virtual machine on Virtual Server 2005 R2 for Commerce Server 2007. While setting it up, I only had access to the Internet via my wireless adapter. Consequently, I had to do the following in order to get the virtual machine to connect to the Internet:
  Install the Virtual Machine Additions.
  On the host machine, go to &amp;ldquo;Add Hardware&amp;rdquo; in Control Panel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2006/11/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2006 01:01:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2006/11/about-me/</guid>
      <description>Update: I have recently joined Microsoft as an Architect Evangelist. This bio will soon change.
I am a technical lead and application architect, specializing in Enterprise Application Integration (EAI), custom .NET applications, and data warehousing solutions. I am largely focused on Microsoft products, including Commerce Server, BizTalk Server, ASP.NET (well, all things .NET), Team Foundation Server (TFS), but I also try to actively participate in the open source community. I am a director for Statera, a Microsoft Gold partner headquartered in Denver, CO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I have been lucky to have so many amazing opportunities throughout my career, working with some of the smartest engineers and technologists in the world and filling various roles from software developer to architect to technology evangelist.
I first started programming in middle school by writing Pascal-based scripts for VT220 telnet clients that automatically played (and leveled) characters in MUDs. Since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on increasingly more complex solutions (if not as fun) including large-scale commerce implementations, low-latency distributed messaging systems, and cloud-based Monte Carlo simulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wade Wegner</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/home/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
