<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wade Wegner</title>
    <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Wade Wegner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 15:06:27 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.wadewegner.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Training Week-In-Review: January 8, 2023</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2023/01/training-week-in-review-january-8-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 15:06:27 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2023/01/training-week-in-review-january-8-2023/</guid>
      <description>Playing &amp;ldquo;bump&amp;rdquo; with my son and wife during the week.
I think this past week marked a turning point for my training. The last few months have brought challenges that were new for me, and consequently I struggled with recovery and rest. I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to debug and resolve most of those issues, and as a result feel as if I&amp;rsquo;m headed in the right direction.
As this is my first &amp;ldquo;Week-In-Review&amp;rdquo; post, I&amp;rsquo;ll share a few things to set some context:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Return to Blogging</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2023/01/my-return-to-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 15:12:02 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2023/01/my-return-to-blogging/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve sat down and written a blog post. I&amp;rsquo;m humbled to say it took me a few hours to relearn Hugo and get it functioning on my PC. But this post isn&amp;rsquo;t about Hugo, migrating from GitHub Pages to Netlify, nor my decision to archive 12 years of old blog posts.
This blog post is to say, well, I have things I want to say.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mahalo a Aloha, Salesforce</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/2021/01/mahalo-a-aloha-salesforce/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 14:56:45 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/2021/01/mahalo-a-aloha-salesforce/</guid>
      <description>I never thought I’d be writing this blog post, yet here I am. After an incredible five years at Salesforce, it’s time to say “Mahalo a Aloha,” or thank you and goodbye.
I have so much gratitude for my colleagues at Salesforce, our customers, and of course, the fantastic Salesforce community. Never in my career have I felt the sense of mission that I have at Salesforce. The desire to advance the “state-of-the-art” for Salesforce developers was a passion reciprocated by my colleagues, supported by leadership, and always appreciated by our customers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I have been lucky to have so many amazing opportunities throughout my career, working with some of the smartest engineers and technologists in the world and filling various roles from software developer to technology evangelist to product executive.
I first started programming in middle school by writing Pascal-based scripts for VT220 telnet clients that automatically played (and leveled) characters in MUDs. Since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on increasingly more complex solutions (if not as fun) including large-scale commerce implementations, low-latency distributed messaging systems, and building developer platforms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merging code and miles</title>
      <link>https://www.wadewegner.com/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wadewegner.com/home/</guid>
      <description>Sharing my journey as a product manager, midpack ultrarunner, and aspiring brewmaster.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
